Don't forget to Subscribe for resources and help us
Don't forget to Subscribe for resources and help us
Documentary of back-embrナe
Documentary of back-embrナe
Feast of knowledge this month we're having a feast of chemistry
這個月份的知識饗宴 我們就要來一場化學饗宴
I am very honored to invite Professor Zhou Bitai from National Taiwan University
我很榮幸的請到台大的講座教授周碧泰
Also our old colleague for many years
也是我們多年的老同事
Later you will see that he is a very, very capable person
待會你們就可以看到是非常非常能力的人
This is also a workaholic, one person can be used by three people
這個也是工作狂 一個人可以當三人用
his details
他的詳細內容
We also saw beautiful pictures
我們也看到很漂亮的圖片
Please enjoy it later
待會就請大家好好欣賞
Let me first give a brief introduction to our keynote speaker
我先把我們的主講人做簡單的介紹
I just said that he is the current chair professor of National Taiwan University
我剛剛已經說他是台大現任的講座教授
In fact, when I just ate
其實我剛剛吃飯的時候
He did very, very broadly
他做得非常非常的廣
He probably knows everything about chemistry.
凡是化學的 大概都他都懂
Then if the National Science Council or the Ministry of Science and Technology has any problems, please ask him to solve them.
然後這個國科會或者科技部有什麼疑難紮正就請他解決
He is also very good at writing
他也非常會寫
write fast and long
寫得又快又長
So besides teaching in the Department of Chemistry, he is currently
那他目前是除了在化學系教書之外
He is also in charge of National Taiwan University Chemistry
他也負責臺大化學
National Taiwan University National Taiwan University's technology research center for emerging materials and prospective research
臺大臺灣大學的這個新興物質跟前瞻研究的科技研究中心
This is actually the Nano Research Center
這個其實前瞻是奈米研究中心
This is a soft center in National Taiwan University
這個是臺灣大學裡面的一個軟中心
Virtual Center
Virtual Center
that's some research topics
那就是一些研究主題
Then there are some teams in
然後有一些團隊在裡面
work together on a common interest
在共同的興趣裡面一起工作
He was Fu Jen Catholic University in 1970
他是輔仁大學1970
Received the school room in 1989
1989年拿到學室
Then in 1985 in
然後是1985年在
Ph.D. from Florida State University
Florida 州立大學拿到博士
that's there
那在
South Carolina worked as an assistant professor
South Carolina 做過助理教授
seven years
七年
87 to 94
87到94
Chung Cheng University
就被中正大學
recruit back, I remember that time
recruit回來 我記得那時候好像
National Taiwan University is also looking for you
台大也有找你
at Chung Cheng University
那在中正大學
do 2001
做到2001年
The Chemistry Department of Chung Cheng University is in his hands
中正大學化學系在他的手裡
also reborn
也是脫胎換骨
In 2001 we were honored
2001年我們就很榮幸
The Chemistry Department of National Taiwan University found it
台大化學系把它找來
Until now, I used to be in the chemistry department
一直到現在 曾經在化學系
I was also the head of the department anyway.
也當過系主任 反正
he did all the hard work
辛苦的工作他都做過
Actually Zhou Bitai, I remember that I seemed to be
那其實周碧泰我記得我好像是在
you were in berkeley
你在Berkeley的時候就進過
at Berkeley
在Berkeley
Just when I won the Nobel Prize
就是剛拿諾貝爾獎的時候
At that time, you and Su Zhiming went to visit
那時候你跟蘇志明去訪問
he hasn't got it yet
他還沒有拿
then 1985
那就1985
Then he turned out to be physical chemistry
那他原來是在物理化學
cutting chemistry
後來裁料化學
I just heard that he also does organic synthesis
剛剛聽到說他還做有機合成
So I say he is versatile
所以我說他這個多才多藝
Of course, there are countless papers published
那當然發表的paper 無數
And there are quite a lot of important chemical journals
而且是蠻多很重要化學期刊的
this reviewer
這個審查者
Anyway, all the domestic awards
那個反正國內的所有的獎
he has it all
他都全包了
Course Ministry Academic Awards
當然教育部的學術獎
National Trophy
國家獎座
Distinguished Award of the National Science Council, etc.
國科會的傑出獎等等
Internationally
在國際上
he is also
他也都是
Royal Society of Chemistry
英國皇家化學會
Rose Society
Rose Society的
Fellow
Fellow
Asia Photochemical
亞洲光化學
Achievement Award
成就獎
in Japan
是在日本大拜
recently
最近
at this
在這個
Uncle Van Thieme
Uncle Van Thieme
This is probably currently
這個是大概目前
Top of the line in chemistry
化學最頂尖的
Journal
Journal
has published his
有刊登他的
Authere profile
Authere profile
I guess I'll cut the blah blah blah anyway.
我想我廢話少說反正這個
There are so many medals, so there is no need to go here
勳章非常非常的多就不必在這裡
then we'll be fine
那我們就好好
Come and enjoy this chemical feast
來做來享受這個化學饗宴
I welcome to be a professor
我歡迎做教授
thank you thank you
謝謝謝謝謝謝
It's so hard to prepare an academic speech.
要準備學術演講 難太多了
It's really too difficult because to talk about it is to say
真的難太多了 因為要講到就是說
understandable and then another point
可以懂 然後又是又有一點
At least chemically, why would it hold him together?
起碼在化學上幹嘛 能把他連在一起
It took days, basically
花了好幾天了 基本上
Then I guess I'm just taking this opportunity
那我想我就是藉這個機會
Then I would like to talk about some of the people in my laboratory.
然後講一下就是說大概在我實驗室裡面的某些
i find it interesting
我覺得蠻有趣
Then everyone can listen
那大家可以聽聽看
I mean, what's interesting about chemistry?
就是說化學上有什麼有趣的事情
to derive him
再去衍生他
So I probably use this today
所以我今天大概就是用這種
It means that my lab develops some interesting molecules
就是說我實驗室發展一些有趣的分子
some nanomaterials
一些奈米機材
Of course I have many, many things that I haven't said
當然我有很多很多沒有講
Because sorry, it's just two hours
因為很抱歉 就是兩小時
I can't finish talking for five hours
五小時我講不完
basically speaking
基本上來講的話
so i just pick these
所以我就是挑這些
I think one thing can make you feel like saying
我認為一件事情可以讓你們覺得說
I have learned something to say about this matter
我有收穫到某些東西來講這個事情
teacher tell you
老師跟你講
Just be a teacher
就做老師就知道
To speak until students understand
要講到學生懂
that was difficult
那是很困難的
a lot of luggage, that's a completely different one, ok, let's take a look
很多的行李,那是完全不同的一個,OK,我們看一下
What about my lab, basically
那我的實驗室呢,基本上還講到
Sorry, I use Chinese like this, ah, it’s safe, because I can’t translate them into that one by one
對不起,我用中文這樣,啊,這卒篤安全,因為我沒辦法一個一個都翻成那個
As for my laboratory, Vice President Wang also talked about it just now
那我的實驗室,剛剛那個王副院長也講過
Actually, I was born to actually do this
其實呢,我的出生事實上是在做這些
uh, fast ray, laser these
呃,快速的雷,雷射的這些
These dynamics, spectral dynamics, OK, so actually I
這些動力學,光譜動力學,OK,所以其實我
When I was in Bokri, what did I do in Bokri
我在博克里的時候,在博克里來說幹嘛
In fact, they are all heavy duty, just doing these things
其實都是heavy duty,就完全在做這些
How to get the laser and why, so I am very familiar with Li Renzhe's laboratory
怎麼去弄雷射來幹嘛幹嘛,所以我跟李仁哲的實驗室很熟很熟
Because we're doing this, OK
因為我們在做這方面,OK
Basically speaking, this piece is still my center
那基本上來講說,這塊還是我的中心
It’s laser spotosphate, OK, that’s all about lasers
就是雷射spotosphate,OK,就雷射的這些
The optical physics block is still my center, but the center has developed
光物理塊還是我的中心,但是中心發展出來
In fact, based on the current spectral dynamics, it is probably the most chemically
其實以目前的光譜動力學,其實大概化學上最
The fastest one is our non-bird laser, just 10-15 times
最快的那個就是我們這座非鳥雷射,就10-15次方
To the 10-14th power second, ah, some people say, hey, the Ato laser is faster
到10-14次方秒,啊有人說,欸,那Ato雷射比較更快
It is 10-18, which is very difficult to do in chemistry, because
就是10-18,那個在化學已經很難做了,因為
Ladies and gentlemen, if you have some physical fundamentals, sea cucumbers are not only there
各位如果有些物理的根本是,海參吧不止都在
You can tell, when you were ten minus 18, square seconds
你可以講說,當你是十的負18、四方秒的時候
Your energy band is already so wide, for me, the state you can explore in chemistry
你的能帶已經這麼寬,對我來講,化學上你能去探究的State
There are almost none, except you are atomic
已經幾乎沒有,除了你是atomic那種
What ES-Opto, 2S-Opto, can do this
什麼ES-Opto,2S-Opto,就可以這樣做
In terms of chemistry, we don’t actually discuss these things in Aton.
那化學上其實我們並不討論這種,Aton裡面的這些東西
Our last time Aton, Aton
我們上次Aton、Aton
Just atom, atom, try to translate into Chinese for me
就原子,原子,對我盡量翻成中文
These so-called molecules made of atoms and atoms, OK, we use the molecular state
原子跟原子組成的這些所謂的分子,OK,我們用分子狀態
So this is still my center
所以這個還是我的中心
Then after I was in the center, in fact, since I came to South Carolina
那我在中心以後呢,事實上從我來南卡
Then I went back to Zhongzheng and went to National Taiwan University
然後回到中正,到了台大
In fact, I have been spending and expanding my field along the way
其實就一路上一直spent,一直擴大我的領域
In fact, the most likely is after the National Taiwan University, that is, the ten years
其實最大大概就是在台大以後,就是這個十幾年
Probably spread from this place, OK
大概就從這個地方一直擴散,OK
For example, I do a lot of very basic science
譬如說我做很多那種非常的基礎的科學
OK, just now, that is to say
OK,剛剛來講,就是說
For example, do some straight-to-direct transfer, direct-to-electricity transfer, energy transfer
比如說做一些什麼直直轉移、電直轉移、能量轉移
i do this a lot
我做很多這方面
But from this direct transfer, I will tell some development
可是從這個直直轉移,我就跟一些發展說
Why is it transferred directly, because there is a relationship between inner clarity and clarity
為什麼直直轉移,因為有內清見、有清見的關係
So I started to design the ring
所以親戒呢我就開始設計說
What can be kissed and what can be done
這親戒哪些可以親戒哪些可以去做
Do get stuck together with other molecules
做跟其他的分子去卡在一起
Then do some identification functions
然後去做一些辨識的功能
so I do a lot of this
所以我做很多這個方面
That's because to do this
那因為要做這個方面
You have to work with him on this one
這份子你要跟他合作
But cooperation is sorry
可是合作很抱歉
Just now the dean Fang Fuyuan said
剛剛那個方復原理院長講
I am a person who spends more than fifteen hours a day
我是一天要用十五小時以上的人
So no one is following me
所以沒有人跟上我的腳步了
i really didn't lie to you
我真的沒有騙你
Absolutely no one is following in my footsteps
絕對沒有人跟上我的腳步
so come by yourself later
所以後來就自己來
OK, so I'm going to start compositing myself.
OK 所以就自己來自己開始做合成
start with materialization
從物化開始
start learning how to synthesize
就開始學怎麼合成
why do what
幹嘛幹嘛幹嘛
on the way
就一路上
do some bio recognition
做一些什麼bio recognition
How to get to the detection of bio
怎麼去bio的這個探測
wait a minute we'll talk about some
等一下我們會講一些
OK
OK
even just said
甚至剛剛也講
We're going to start developing these
我們就要開始發展這些
how to carry these
怎麼去carry這些
how to take these molecules
怎麼去帶這些分子
What the hell body
幹嘛 到底的body
So we do a lot of nano science
所以我們做很多的nano science
basically
基本上
Therefore, in terms of Nami materials
所以在耐米機材方面
I will do quite a lot
我會做蠻多的
From 2003 to 2004
從2003 2004年那時候
When science in Taiwan and Macao rises
台澳科學抬頭的時候
make a lot of glowing materials
做很多發光材料
The material of this perm energy
這個燙能的這方面的材料
OK basically
OK 基本上
so you know along the way
所以一路上你就知道說
Dean Wangfu said just now
剛剛旺福院長說
I probably cover everything in chemistry
大概化學上我全包
Basically OK to some extent
基本上某種程度來講 OK
You said that there is deepening here
你說在這邊有深化
Yes wait a minute I'll talk about deepening OK basically
有 等一下我會講深化 OK 基本上
you'll know it when you hear it
你聽一下就知道
so but anyway
所以但是呢 不管怎麼樣
what i'm talking about
我講的其實都是什麼
very simple is
很簡單 就是
It's chemistry and light
就是化學跟 light
Because light is OK after all
因為畢竟光 OK
That's what you said, that's the light
就是你們講 就是那個光
OK, that light is basically for me
OK 那個光基本上對我來講
is my specialty
就是我的專長
OK so I've been doing
OK 所以我一直在做
The so-called mechanism of light and chemistry
所謂的光跟化學的機檔
OK basically OK
OK 基本上來講的話 OK
how from chemistry
怎麼從化學上面
wait a minute i will bring a lot
等一下我會帶很多
show mode come over ok basically
表演模式過來 OK 基本上
so that's how to get to the stalls what to do
所以這就是怎麼去機檔幹嘛幹嘛
This is probably my basic one
這大概就是我基本上的一個
Center thinking OK in this place
中心的思維 OK 在這個地方
Of course one thing is
那當然一件事情就是
so of course one thing
所以當然一件事情
What I'm going to talk about today is probably molecules
我今天要講的大概就是分子
Deepen the molecular ratio of the machine material, which is basically
深化分子 代比機材這基本上
Probably I will cover this inside
大概我都會涵蓋這是裡面
What about these areas?
那在這幾個領域裡面呢
I'll probably talk about three of them.
我大概就會講 挑三個來講
One is OK to talk about these so-called clear-eyed elements
一個就講這些所謂清見分子的 OK
I'll start with the basics OK
我會從最基本的來講 OK
clear viewer
就是清見分子
Because after all, it's more common sense
因為畢竟這是比較通識的
Some elements of internal and external clarity
一些內清見跟外清見的分子
what physical properties it has
它什麼物理特性
What are its photophysical properties?
它什麼光物理特性
What properties does it have when illuminated
它在照光以後會有什麼特性
I will talk about this
這個我都會講
Then one very important thing is to say
然後很重要一件事情就是說
water is clear
水也是有清見
So how to see inside from the clear water
所以怎麼從水的清見裡面
go call it
去把它所謂的
untie what we want
解取出來說我們要的東西
Then I can go and probe the water
然後我可以去探測水
This water certainly does not mean our water
這水當然不是說我們的水
That is to say, the water in biochemical
就是說在生化裡面的水
This is a very important and most urgent development for me
這是我一個很重要的最緊急的發展
Also I want to be at Nano Airport
另外我想在奈米機場
some listeners like to listen
有些聽手滿喜歡聽的
Basically, let me talk about some nano-airports in semiconductors
基本上講我講一下半導體的一些奈米機場
Especially now the hardest thing is
尤其現在最夯的就是
The entire industry in Taiwan will be defeated
全台灣的產業界都會被打敗的
These are the so-called frame pains
就是這些所謂的框疼道
quantum dot display
量子點的顯示器
Let me tell you that everyone in Taiwan is panicking now
我跟你講現在台灣每個都風聲鶴唳
Said that the industry said that this would not leave
說產業界說這個再不走的話
Taiwan is probably all cut off
台灣大概就是全部都被砍掉了
wait a minute listen
等一下你聽聽看
there's something i'll talk about
有一些我會講一下的東西
And Nano Airport
而且奈米機場
Composite material, OK, basically
的複合材料,OK,基本上
So, what I'm talking about today is probably
所以呢,我今天講的大概就是
Among the seven or eight fields, these are four fields
這個七八個領域裡面的,這是四個領域
That's like Solar Energy Cell, or
那像Solar Energy Cell啦,或者是
I probably don’t know much about O-ray, so I won’t talk about it
O-ray這個方面,我大概不太會,我就不講了
Because I know I've seen the one before you, like
因為我知道我看過你們前面那個,像
Chen Jindi, what, many people have said this
陳錦蒂啊,什麼,很多人他們都講過這些
What kind of luminescent material is used for what, so this place
什麼發光材料幹嘛幹嘛,所以這個地方
I probably won't talk about it, I'll just focus on
我大概就不講了,我就專注在
These few, these four are probably
這幾個,這四個大概就是
Molecules of this aspect of Qingjian
清見的這個方面的分子
OK, and then I will talk about some unavoidable materials
OK,然後再講一些難免機材
Probably in this place, okay, OK
大概在這個地方,好不好,OK
So first I will talk about some so-called
所以第一個我就講一些所謂的
Seeing Molecules Inside Clearly, This Is Interesting in Photophysics
內清見分子,這是有趣的光物理
It's really interesting, OK, you'll know when you listen to it
真的很有趣,OK,等一下聽一看就知道
OK, let's talk about the catalysis of water molecules
OK,然後再講水分子的催化
OK, from water molecule catalysis, how do I go
OK,從水分子催化,我怎麼去
To measure these water molecules in biochemistry
去看測在生化裡面的這些水分子
Let me tell you one more thing, I haven’t said it here yet, but I’ll do it too
我再講一個,我在這邊還沒講,倒狗我也講好了
Why do you talk about the Dynamic of Protin?
大家講Protin的這個Dynamic幹嘛幹嘛幹嘛
Just use it as a protin and have something
就用做Protin有個什麼
Any transfer in or what to do, look at its Dynamic
Any transfer進去或幹嘛,看它的Dynamic
Or do what QuickStore does, I do it in reverse
或是做QuickStore幹嘛幹嘛,我是反過來做
I am using
我是用
Use the water in Protin to detect the activity of Protin
用Protin裡面的水去探測Protin的活性
OK, so this is a different approach
OK,所以這是不一樣的一個approach
This is probably the first in the world, no one has done this before
這個大概是全世界第一個吧,沒有人這樣做過了
OK, basically, so we'll know when we hear it
OK,基本上,所以我們聽聽看就知道
OK, so let me start with these few
OK,所以開始我先講這幾個
These are the things that you can see
就是清見的這些東西
what is its molecule like
它的分子是什麼樣的情形
Well, I actually did this two months ago
那這個其實我在兩個月前
The one who thinks before this so-called commemoration
在這個所謂的紀念前思量的那個
When I made the list, I talked about some
那個名單的時候,我講過一些
OK, but today because it's an hour and a half or more
OK,但是今天因為是一個半鐘頭或以上
OK, so I'll just put a more comprehensive
OK,所以我就把一個更comprehensive
OK, it's more detailed, I'll put it in the second place
OK,就是更仔細的我會把它講歸次
OK, sorry, I can speak English, I can’t help it, it’s still a matter
OK,抱歉,講一講會講英文,沒辦法,還是事情
OK, let's take a look, then you have to talk about Qingjian
OK,我們看一下,那你要講到清見
OK, let's talk about Nei Qingjian, talk about these molecules
OK,講到內清見,講到這些分子的話
you start pointing now
你現在從指指開始講
I won’t go into more about fingering, as fingering has a physical definition
那指指我就不多講了,指指都有物理上的定義
Let me tell you that three crackers make one finger, OK
就跟你講說三個垮克就成了一個指指嘛,OK
We won't talk about this much, this high-energy physics
這個我們就不多講,這個高能物理
It seems that several high-energy physics have talked about it here, OK
好像高能物理好幾個還在這邊講過了,OK
We don't talk about this thing, we can talk about chemistry or biochemistry
我們不講這個東西,化學或生化地址就可以講
Then this is normal, it’s H positive, isn’t it?
那這個普通嘛,就是H正嘛,不是嗎
If H is positive, the most famous one is to tell you about the acid-base of Arrhinius
H正的話,這最有名的就是跟你講說阿蕊尼烏斯的酸鹼
Just tell you that you can release a proton, this is sour
就跟你講說可以release一個proton,這就是酸嘛
that's basically it, right?
這基本上來講,對不對
If you want to talk about it, that's fine. If you talk about address biochemistry, what about sour fish?
如果你要講就好,如果說地址生化幹嘛,那酸魚啊
That is, proton has sour fish, the formation of mesohalite
就是proton有酸魚,中滷石的形成
Right, let me tell you in terms of biochemistry, we call it Zhizhi BOM
對不對,生化上就跟你講說,我們叫直指BOM
OK, this, I only found out this time during the preparation, this is called BOM, OK, basically
OK,這個,這次準備才知道,這叫BOM,OK,基本上
Just proton BOMP, POMP
就proton BOMP,POMP
The promb pump, of course the most famous, is very simple?
那promb pump,當然最有名,就很簡單嗎?
That is, if you want to get from the cells inside
就是如果說你要從裡面的細胞裡面的話
To pump it out, basically you have energy for it
要把它pump出來的話,基本上你就有個能量給它
Just turn it into ATP, OK, release a proton
就是把它轉成ATP,OK,release一個proton
Basically you just let the energy out, pump it out from here
基本上你就能量就讓它什麼,從這邊pump出來
If you need energy, it's simple, you make a very simple
如果你需要能量,很簡單,你就做一個很簡單的
CAMME Osmosis, is what we call chemical osmosis
CAMME Osmosis,就是我們叫化學滲透
If you just let it go back, you can gain energy
你就讓它回去的話,你就可以 gain energy
OK, so proton is in the whole biochemistry or physics or chemistry
OK,所以說proton在整個生化或物理或化學
In fact, its significance is very, very, very important
其實它的意義是非常非常非常重大的
Then there is proton, one thing we want to talk about next is to talk about Hydrogen BOM
那有proton,下來我們要講一件事情就是講Hydrogen BOM
The Hydrogen BOM, basically
那Hydrogen BOM,基本上就是
It's the Qing sword, right?
就是清劍嘛 對不對
Then Qing Jian will tell you one thing, that is
那清劍就跟你講一件事情就是說
If we speak in chemistry
如果我們在化學來講的話
The most famous one is Sharing the Sword
最有名的就是共駕劍
Yes, how long is it built for sharing the sword?
對 共駕劍的它建長多少呢
If with a single sword
如果以一個單劍的話
That's about 1 to 1.5 n cool
那就是差不多1到1.5個n爽
is i
就是i
It is 10's -8cm
就是10的-8cm
10'-10m
10的-10米
right, it's almost that long
對不對 就是差不多這麼長
How do we define Qingjian?
那清劍我們怎麼定義呢
Generally speaking
一般來講的話
Here is written OK
這邊有寫 OK
In fact, the earliest definition of the Qing sword was in 1912
其實清劍最早定義是1912年的
Oh it's so early OK basically speaking
喔 這這麼早 OK 基本上來講的話
OK that's usually a mess
OK 那一般都亂七八糟
By 2011 IUPEC
到2011年IUPEC
It's the International Naming Association telling you
就是國際命名協會就跟你講說
how to define don't care
怎麼定義 不要管什麼
How did we make the Qing sword before?
以前我們怎麼做出清劍
it's very simple
就是很簡單嘛
This so-called highly electronegative
這個所謂的陰電性高的
Right? Follow up what happened
對不對 跟清產生的
OK, basically it’s called Youqing Sword, right?
OK 基本上就叫有清劍 對吧
That is to say, eggs, sheep
就是說蛋啊 羊啊
These things serve again
這些東西又服務啊
But what about the current basic definition
可是呢 現在的基本定義
just tell you one thing is
就跟你講一件事情是
any chemical bond
任何一個chemical bond
OK as long as there is a follow-up
OK 只要跟清有產生
in this kind of
在這種 不管是
No matter the geometry, you squeeze it to that place
不管是幾何 你把它擠到那個地
It doesn't matter what it is, as long as it is 1.5 to 2.2 N pairs
或幹嘛都沒有關係 只要是1.5到2.2個N雙的
Basically we just generalize it
基本上我們就把它歸納
Something similar to CH can also be seen clearly with other itineraries
某種類似CH也可以跟其他行程清見
OK, basically let me give you an example, this one was published in the last three months
OK 基本上我舉個例子 上三個月才發表的這個
OK, both zero and green can produce clear vision
OK 零跟青都可以產生清見
Because there are 2.1 N pairs in the middle
因為這中間就是2.1個N雙
OK 2.1 I so say in terms of the modern version of Kiyomi
OK 2.1個I 所以就現代版的清見說
This is called Qingjian, so Qingjian is already what it is
這個叫清見 所以清見已經是什麼
very very popular
非常非常的popular
OK basically put it this way okay let's see
OK 基本上是用這種方式來講 好 我們看一下來
So in terms of this structure
所以以這個架構來講的話
Let's take a look at one thing, in terms of chemistry
我們來看看一件事情 就是化學件來講的話
What's going on with Qing Jian?
清見到底怎麼樣 我們看 共架件的話
About 30 to 100 kcal of energy
大概30到100千卡的能量
is that it will stabilize you at 30 to 100 kcal
就是它會讓你穩定下來 在30到100千卡
We all know that van der Valli is very weak at about 0.1 kcal, OK
那凡德瓦利我們都知道在0.1千卡左右就很弱很弱 OK
The energy of the long temperature is also about 0.1 0.5 kcal
那長溫的那個能量也是差不多0.1 0.5千卡
Even the long-term temperature of 298K is very weak.
就是長溫298K 這個都是很弱的
The Hydrogen stick is somewhere in between, about 1.2 to 10 kcal
那Hydrogen棒就介乎這個之間 大概1.2到10千卡
OK this different one Kiyomi
OK 這個不同的一個清見
I am listing these relatively strong clear views in the past.
我這樣列出來就是以前的這些比較強的清見
I just kept it, eggs, why can I see it clearly?
就養的啦 蛋啦幹嘛 才能清見
we'll see later
等一下我們看下來就知道
Probably about 1.2 to 10 kcal
大概都是差不多1.2到10千卡
Fu is an exception
福是比較例外的
Because we think that there is ionized clear view
因為福我們認為是有離子化的清見
Generally speaking, it is about 1.2 to 10 kcal.
一般來講大概是1.2到10千卡這個地方
then why do you want to see clearly
那為什麼要清見?很簡單嘛
Just to tell you it can also be seen by pedestrians
就跟你講說它也可以行人見
can also be what? in a way just take it off
也可以什麼呢?在某種程度就脫掉
able to reformation
能reformation
reformation
reformation
what is this ? biochemically it needs
這才是什麼?在生化上它需要嘛
it needs to be this way
它就需要這種方式啊
You can't use your words so tightly
你不可能用你說見這麼緊的話
So how does it do these metabolisms
那它怎麼做這些metabolism
It's the metabolism. It's impossible.
就是新陳代學 不可能啊
so this is why
所以這個就是為什麼
Wait a minute we talk about the base pale of DNA
等一下我們講到DNA的base pale
that's what it does, in a way
它就是這種功能 某種程度來講
OK
OK
ok, see you in chemistry
好 那化學見
When it comes to chemistry, I have to talk about this person, right?
講到化學見不得不講到這個人對不對
Chemical see these words chemical bound
化學見這幾個字 chemical bound
What is this bund for?
這是bund幹嘛幹嘛
In fact, it is when it is in class
其實都是它在上課的時候
It has not been published
它也沒有發表過啊
I wrote it on the blackboard during class.
都上課的時候就寫在黑板上的
This Berkely professor is called G.N. Lewis
這個Berkely的教授叫做G.N. Lewis
You know, Lewis acid test
知道吧 路易式酸檢
you should know right
你應該知道對不對
But your G.N. Lewis actually it
可是你的G.N. Lewis其實它
He is not the most famous doctor Lu acid test
他最有名並不是陸醫生酸檢
he is the father of thermodynamics
他是熱力學的祖宗
is the ancestor of chemical thermodynamics
就是化學熱力學的祖宗
basically talk
基本上來講話
OK but everyone remembers that he is
OK 但是大家記得他就是
Doctor Lu acid test
陸醫生酸檢
Basically OK
基本上來講 OK
That's when he was experimenting in Burkley
那這是他在Burkley做實驗的時候
Speaking of this place
講到這個地方
I have one under here
我這邊下面就有一個
compare that
比較那個
In fact, what are we talking about?
其實我們講什麼棒什麼棒
OK let's see one thing
OK 我們看看一件事情
Right, you can find it from Google
對不對 你從Google裡面可以找
Google he recently helped
Google他最近幫
Do not believe you can now key
不信你現在可以key
About 5.7 million B
大概570萬B
OK but this kind of thing
OK 可是這種東西
I think 5 million is enough, right?
我覺得說500千萬已經夠多了對不對
It's far worse than the entertainment industry
跟娛樂界比就差太多了
OK entertainment
OK 娛樂界
Come on, let's see what the next entertainment industry is called
來 我們看看下面一個娛樂界叫什麼呢
What is another stick called?
還有一種棒叫什麼棒
Called James Bond
叫做James Bond
You see James Bond has 85.8 million
你看 James Bond有8,580萬比
So the answer is still much worse.
所以答案是還是差很多啦
Basically you're like the entertainment industry
基本上 你就跟娛樂界
You see, this kind of stick is equally good, but it’s so much worse.
這種棒 你看同樣是棒就差這麼多
OK so there's nothing to say
OK 所以這沒有什麼話說
let's take a look
我們看一下
Okay, what about the scissors?
好 那剪機隊的話
We are role models
我們就是清見的典範
I just changed this English today
我今天才把這個英文換掉
Change to Chinese OK
換成中文 OK
The answer is that we see
那答案是我們看
ATGC is Adding and Siaming or light and shadow and Sitle Sync
ATGC就是Adding跟Siaming或者是光影跟Sitle Sync
look at this clear
你看看這個清見
basically the place
基本上這個地方
Published in 2003
2003年的發表
This JPC publishes
這個JPC發表
Let me tell you that AT has about -11000 cards
就跟你講說AT大概有-11000卡
These two cut together have -11000 calories
這兩個砍在一起有-11000卡
Then let me tell you Kobrenbaum is 50 to 100
那我跟你講Kobrenbaum是50到100
so it's all very
所以這都是很
about five times ten times weaker than it is
比它是弱了大概五倍十倍的
But basically three are stronger
但是基本上三件就比較強
Just one more, about 20 kilocalories
就多一個大概20幾千卡
but more than anything
但是都比什麼
than these so-called carpools
比這些所謂的共駕艦
broken tightly
斷得緊緊的
that's much weaker
那弱很多
so it can be anything
所以它就可以什麼
Breakdown Reformation
Breakdown Reformation
Causes of Breakdown Reformation
Breakdown Reformation的原因
OK just need to see clearly
OK就是需要清見
OK, then you say one is not strong enough
OK那你說一個不夠強
That's all right
沒關係啊
The whole cassette is strong enough.
整個卡帶就夠強了吧
If you say something like this you don't believe
如果說你不信的這種東西
I want you to always trust Gweaver Organic
要你們總信格魏佛有機
right
對不對
just one line won't work
就是一條線不行
Then tie thousands of threads and you won't be able to move
然後綁幾千個線你就動不了
OK so maybe one thing
OK所以大概一件事情
it's obvious to tell you
這很明顯就跟你講說
The biggest advantage of Kiyomi is in this place
清見的最大好處就是在這個地方
OK will obviously give you this kind of sense
OK很明顯就給你一個這種Sense
good
好
That's clear
那清見其實
You said from 1912 to now
你說1912到現在
a hundred years
一百年
Exactly 102 years, 103 years
剛好102年,103年
But one big thing is still a Hot topic
但是大一件事情還是一個Hot topic
still a very popular
還是一個非常熱門的
For example, the recent ones, look at last year's ones
譬如說最近的,你看去年還前年的
let's see this, shall we
我們看這個,對不對
this is a molecule
這個就是一個分子
called A-hydroxyquinoline
叫做A-hydroxyquinoline
leave it alone
就不管它
Look at this when it's cold
你看這個在低溫的時候
Atomic Force Microscopy FM
用原子力顯微鏡FM
Atomic force microscope you also see
原子力顯微鏡你還看出
Seems like Kiyomi is here
好像有清見在這邊
look at this place
你看這個地方
These are here
這個這幾個在這邊
seems clear
好像看起來有清見
look like this
你看光是這樣子
It was published in Science
它就發表在Science
This is the mainland
這是大陸的這個
It should be Chinese Academy of Sciences
應該是中科院吧
basically
基本上來講
that developed
那發展出來
but after a year or two
可是過了一兩年
was overthrown after a year
過了一年以後就被推翻
this may be problematic
這可能是有問題的
Everyone, if you say it has physics, you will know it.
各位如果說有物理性就知道說
because they found out
因為他們發覺說
you use an atomic force microscope
你用原子力顯微鏡
For example, look at this Compound
譬如說看這個Compound
this molecule
這個分子
You see, this molecule is egg-and-egg
你看這個分子這邊是蛋跟蛋
Vice President Wang, look at this
這個王副院長看這個
must know better than me
一定比我清楚多
because he said he was ejaculating
因為他說在解精的
You see, the eggs are not clear at all
你看這個蛋跟蛋根本沒有清見
egg on egg
蛋就蛋
egg to egg
蛋跟蛋之間
He still sees this
他還是看到這條
So answering one thing is that it is difficult
所以答一件事情是這是分難的
ok, he thinks there is a problem with this clear view
ok 他就認為說這個清見是有問題的
It means don't underestimate
意思就是說不要小看喔
Of course you often see why rigorously choose Weijing
當然你常看嚴謹選維境幹嘛幹嘛
What would you say when you saw glasses on WeChat?
你會說什麼看到了眼鏡微信
What may be the artifact
有可能是什麼artifact
It may be the artifact that it appeared in the experiment
有可能根本就是實驗上它出現的artifact
this is something that is often seen
這是經常看到的事情
So I'm telling you to be careful, be careful
所以就跟你講說這要很小心很小心
Recently because of this post
最近因為有這篇以後
All I know look at AFFM or STM
所有我知道看AFFM或STM的
are being scrutinized very carefully
都被非常小心的在審視
Especially if it can be published on the Lianyiqiu series
尤其是能發表在聯益球系列以上的話
will probably be scrutinized
大概都會被審視
But from here it can be said
但是從這個地方就可以講
It's important to call it Hide and Keep on
叫做Hide and Keep on很重要
basically
基本上來講
Generally speaking, what do we think about the topic?
一般來講我們在話題上怎麼看呢
That's easy, just watch an ordinary MMA
那就簡單嘛 就看一個普通MMA
why? let me give you an example
為什麼呢 我舉個例子
You also know that the clearer the stronger
你也知道清見越強
Basically there are fewer electrons on this side
基本上這邊的電子越少
as we call it inside the direct nuclear tool
就我們叫做在直指核子工具裡面
it becomes more shift
它就越當shift
The more when the field shift
越當field shift
in this longer place
在這個越長的地方
outdated place
越在過時的地方
This molecule is synthesized by us
這個分子是我們合成的
You know there's an inward arrow over here
你就知道這邊有個內傾箭
There's an inward arrow
這邊有個內傾箭
OK, didn't you just say that?
OK,那剛剛不是講過嗎?
N and OH are stronger
N跟OH是比較強的
N, OH and OH are relatively weak
N,OH跟OH是比較弱的
So let's just say, this place is what
所以我們就算,這個地方就是什麼
This is its protein
這個就是它的protein
is its direct point, this is its direct point
就是它的直指,這個就是它的直指
So we look at it this way
所以我們是用這樣來看說
it really has introverted arrows
它真的是有內傾箭
Because it exceeds, as long as it exceeds MMA, exceeds 10
因為超過,只要超過MMA、超過10
Probably what the slope of this place should be
大概這個地方的傾應該就是什麼
produced by inward arrows
是內傾箭產生的
We look at it in this very simple way
我們是用這種很簡單的方式來看
Well, here is a very special one
好,那這邊就有一個很特殊
What about water, water is the most special thing, why
那水呢,水是最特殊的嘛,為什麼
One water has several falling arrows, four falling arrows
一個水有幾個傾箭,四個傾箭
A word of water, you see
一個水的話,你看
It can all form arrows, OK, basically
它都可以形成傾箭,OK,基本上來講的話
So it's the single molecule that provides the highest arrow density in nature
所以它是自然間裡面能提供最高傾箭密度的單一分子
one thing for sure
確實的一件事情
And look at this place, it's starting to form ice
那你看這個地方,它開始形成冰了
it's starting to form ice, ok, basically
它開始形成冰了,OK,基本上來講的話
It's a calculation, it's starting to form ice
這是一個計算,它開始形成冰
If you look at this place
那你看這個地方的話
Generally speaking, we talk about
那一般來講,我們講說
There should be someone who is making energy water, OK, basically speaking
這裡面應該有在做能量水的,OK,基本上來講的話
this
這個
Basically, all energy water is
基本上其實所有能量水就是
It forms different, this is still hexagonal packing
它形成不同的,這還是六方堆積
but what makes a difference
但是形成不同的什麼
Different from what we call the People's Gang
不同的我們叫做國人幫的理
It forms the principle of different Chinese gangs, ok
就形成不同國人幫的理,ok
Then some people said, ah, why are these different energies?
那有人就說,啊,這是不同能量幹嘛幹嘛幹嘛
Actually it's all one
其實它都是一個
A hexagonal closest packing is actually the same
一個六方最密堆積其實都是一樣
It's different only in what
它不一樣的地方只是在什麼
It is polycrystalline
它是polycrystalline
How fine is this polycrystalline?
這個polycrystalline呢,多精細呢
can give you a different way
可以給你不同的這個方式
Then tell me, does this have any different energy?
那你說,這有沒有什麼不同的能量
I don't dare to tell you that I do scientific research
我做科研的不敢跟你講
But we've been doing this different shape recently
但是我們最近在做這種不同形狀的
ok, cause this is under different pressure
ok,因為這在不同的壓力之下幹嘛
you can form different words
你可以形成不同的話
We found that we hacked our molecules into here
我們發現我們把我們的分子砍到這裡面來
Its radiance is not quite the same
它的放光的情形不是很一樣
ok, but this has nothing to do with energy water
ok,但是這跟什麼能量水是沒有關係
I just want to tell you one thing, that this is actually
我只跟你講一件事情,說這個其實就是
It is a so-called polycrystalline
它是一個所謂的polycrystalline
it's so detailed
就是多精細的
Ok, how fine this is depends on different environments
ok,這個多精細是隨著不同環境幹嘛
it can make a difference, it's true
它可以產生不同,這是確實的
I admit it
這一點我承認
Does it have any energy? I dare not admit it
那有沒有什麼能量,我不敢承認
ok, but because from a scientific point of view, but it does
ok,但是因為從科研角度,但是它確實
actually there is a difference
其實是有不同的
Okay, so let's talk about Chizi and Qingjian
好 所以講到池子講到清見
ok now talk about pool transfer
ok 現在講池子轉移
because wait a minute my main
因為這等一下我的主要的
main central idea
主要的這個中心思維
ok transfer in pool
ok 在池子轉移
what pool transfer
什麼池子轉移
The easiest thing to think about is acid-base neutralization.
想的最簡單就是酸鹼中和嘛
Acid-base neutralization you see
酸鹼中和你看
it's a sour
這是一個酸
It's an alkali, right?
這是個鹼對不對
Ah, what is acid-base neutralization?
啊 什麼叫酸鹼中和
Just throw this acid to
就是把這個酸丟給
Eh, common, if it is the acid of Arrhenius
欸 普通 假如說是阿瑞尼烏斯的酸
throw it to him
就把丟給他
This is what was originally thrown to him at this place
就這個本來在這個地方丟給他
ok, this is acid-base neutralization
ok 這個就是酸鹼中和嘛
Isn't acid-base neutralization just to transfer the pool?
那酸鹼中和那不是就是把池子轉移嗎
This is the same reason, ok, normal
這一樣道理 ok 普通程度
Well this is in all of our modalities
好 這是在我們的所有的機態
It's what you call everything you see
就是你所謂看到的萬事萬物幹嘛
No light, no time in this excited state
沒有照光 沒有在這個激發態的時候
ok you see this
ok 你看到這樣子
But when in the excited state
可是那在激發態的時候
that's more serious we like
那更嚴重 我們看好
We say that when the pool shifts to an electronically excited state
我們說池子轉移在電子激發態的時候
more likely to happen
更容易發生
ok this is in this basic state
ok 這個是在這個基礎態的時候
ok is in the most stable state
ok 就是在最穩定態的時候
This is lighting several examples
這個是在照光 好幾個例子
Let's do our part
我們看本分
Oh, but it's your duty to know
喔 可是本分知道嘛
But duty is often used
可是本分常常用
If you activate H-mea, it will be light, light paper
你如果激發 H-mea就是光 光紙
illuminate with light
把激發 用光照光
light it up
照光把它激發
What about after the excitation?
激發以後呢
very simple thing
很簡單一件事情
I'll tell you about chemistry
化學上就跟你講說
You excite it is to put this electron
你把它激發就是把這個電子
ok we call Pai Electronics
ok 我們叫做拍電子
T to excited state
T到激發態
that's what we call counterintelligence
就是我們叫做反間諜
Shoot Star, Call Anti-Spies
拍Star 叫反間諜
Then you also know that we are from the middle school
那你也知道就是我們從國中
start learning
就有開始學
ok here if you have kids
ok 這邊如果小孩子的話
Sorry, there is no way in middle school
抱歉 國中就沒辦法
you can talk
就可以講說
why would you
你為什麼會
there will be this turtle ring
會有這個烏龜環
That is to conform to the beat electron of 4n plus 2
那就是要符合4n加2的拍電子
I don't mean to say
不是想說啊
Just 6 beat electrons in this place
就6個拍電子在這個地方
Is 4n equal to 1?
4n等於1嘛
ok you drop an electron T
ok 你把一個電子T掉
It becomes unstable when it becomes five beat electrons
變成五個拍電子才會不穩定
What to do if it is unstable
不穩定怎麼辦
He needs to hurry up and get an electron into it.
他要趕快去拿一個電子進去
where did he get it
他從哪裡拿
If there is an OH here
如果這邊有個OH
Doesn't it have OH itself?
本身不有OH嗎
There's a so-called lone electron
這邊有一個所謂的孤電子
Lonely electricity Lone with electrons, quickly fill in the electrons
孤電 孤帶電子就趕快把電子填進去
Once filled in
一填進去以後
this stable
這個穩定的
But after stabilization
可是穩定以後
After filling this in
這一填進去以後
After becoming less electron
變成少電子以後
This Proton is very sour
這個Proton就非常酸
super sour
超級酸
How sour? Let's see
多酸呢 我們看
basically in
基本本來在
look
你看喔
In fact, the duty lies in
其實本分在
At the time of this GroundState
在這個GroundState的時候
ok we generally see
ok 我們一般看的
9.8 is a bit less
是9.8是有點減
But in the excited state it is -0.1
可是在激發態是-0.1
acidic than sulfuric acid
比硫酸還酸
it is more acidic than sulfuric acid
它比硫酸還酸
So this H will run away
所以這個H就會跑掉
Run away and become O-Fu-H-Zen
跑掉就會變成O-Fu-H-Zen
We call this acid Photosac
我們把這種酸叫做Photosac
When exposed to light, it produces acid that is more acidic than sulfuric acid
照光以後它產生比硫酸還酸
Because this magnetic paper will be thrown away
因為這個磁紙會丟掉
Throwing this into the water means throwing it into the water for hydration.
這個丟掉在水裡面是丟到給水水合了
If we create an environment
如果我們製造一個環境
This environment is after the Proton magnetic paper is thrown away.
這個環境是這個Proton這個磁紙丟掉以後
There is a pair of scissors
有一個剪 剪機對
in this molecule it can accept it
在這個分子裡面它可以接受它
that would be fun
那就很好玩了
Let me give you an example let's look at this
我舉個例子我們看這個
OK, so I'll design a random molecule
好 所以我隨便設計一個分子
This molecule is very acidic after being exposed to light.
這個分子本來這個是照光以後就很酸
But I have a scissors here
可是我在這個地方有個剪
This Pyridine is cut
這個Pyridine就是剪
N is a scissor
N是一個剪
So it would have produced a molecular internal clearance in this place
所以它本來就會產生一個分子的內清剪在這個地方
So after you light it, it is very sour, where will it go?
所以你照光以後這個很酸很酸要到哪去
It's here to cut
它就到剪這個地方來
So after the light was illuminated, the magnetic paper was originally in this place.
所以照光以後本來這個磁紙在這個地方
it switches to this place
它就switch到這個地方
When you switch to this place, you will know one thing is
那switch到這個地方你就知道一件事情是
tell you according to organic chemistry
按照有機化學跟你講說
This whole shoot together will be reassembled once again
這整個拍的共樂就會重組一次
So it's actually isomers
所以它事實上是同分異購物
But this shot is completely different from this shot
但是這個拍跟這個拍是完全不一樣的
So an excitation would have been 330 which is in UV
所以一激發本來是330 這是在UV
What happens when it's triggered
一激發以後就變成什麼
If it becomes different, it emits green light
變得不一樣的話它放光是來綠光
will turn into green light
就會變成是綠光
it's an interesting thing
這很有意思的事情
Then this...
那這個...
You said teacher, what are you doing?
你說老師那你在做什麼東西
You design this thing and we're actually doing spectral dynamics
你設計這個東西我們事實上在做光譜動力學
Just ask this after the light...
就照光以後請問一下這個...
how fast is this finger
這個指指多快
OK how fast and what steps to enter
OK 多快 進入什麼步驟
it will move from here to this place
它會從這邊移走移到這個地方
how fast
到底多快呢
does it have energy
它有沒有能量呢
Why, why, actually we are researching
幹嘛幹嘛 其實我們在研究
but today i won't talk
但今天我不會講
Because of this talk everyone is asleep OK basically
因為這些講大家都睡著了 OK 基本上
But to tell you one thing is I use an animation to tell you
但是跟你講一件事情是我用一個動畫跟你講
OK, for example, this lighting
OK 譬如說這個照光
How fast is it? About the same
它的多快呢 大概差不多是
almost 55
差不多是55個
It's 5.5% to 10's sub-11 and it will pass in ten seconds
就是5.5成10的副11十秒它就會過去了
how did it pass because it was like this
它怎麼過去呢 是因為它這樣
You see it bends like this
你看它整個就這樣彎一下
Then after getting the same Distance
然後得到相同的Distance之後
he came from here
他就從這邊過來
OK, you can see it and say
OK,你就可以看出來說
We are researching this
我們在研究這一方面的
how fast is he
他到底多快
or is he disabled
或者他有沒有能障
why why
幹嘛幹嘛
just this way
就用這種方式
I won't talk today, just talk to you
今天我不會講,只跟你講說
he has this condition
他有這種狀況
well, that excites the transfer in the instruction
好,那激發在指示轉移
in fact, to be honest
事實上,老實講
what are you doing now
現在還在什麼
still researching
還在繼續在研究
And it's a big one
而且還是很大很大的一個
That is to say, last year I organized a
就是說去年我organize一個
A meeting in the United States
一個meeting在美國
Please help me with ACS
就ACS請我幫忙
basically speaking
基本上來講的話
Of course this is our design
那當然這是我們設計
I got this from JPCB
我得這個JPCB的這個
cover award, OK, basically
cover的獎,OK,基本上
we design a
我們就設計一個
You see, after lighting with lightning
你看,用閃電照光以後
After lighting, this pro-tom
照光以後這個pro-tom
come here
跑到這邊來
That's because it's two common
那因為是兩個共同的
One is me and one is at Georgia Tech
一個就是我,一個是在Georgia Tech
OK, so from
OK,所以就是從
Running from Taiwan to Georgia Tech
從台灣跑到Georgia Tech
we would have written
我們本來就寫
Why are you writing it here?
幹嘛都寫在這個地方
Then what is the NPU Logo doing?
然後NPU的Logo幹嘛
later rejected
後來被否決掉
It was rejected by the mainland, OK, basically speaking
被大陸否決掉,OK,基本上來講的話
so this won't work
所以這個不行
But it's like this now, ok
但是現在就這個樣子,OK
basically tell you he is still this
基本上就跟你講說他還是這個是
This was posted last month
這才上上個月發的
basically speaking
基本上來講的話
So he is still a big group
所以他還是一個很大的group
Especially in Europe doing this
尤其是歐洲那邊做這種
Fundamental Science的
Fundamental Science的
so much really
好多好多真的是
And the functions of Europeans are different
而且歐洲人開的功能不一樣
When we have a meeting, we go outside the door to chat
我們開會是開開到門外去聊聊天
Why, what, the flash is gone
幹嘛幹嘛 閃都不見了
the european sits over there
那歐洲人就坐在那邊
He won't leave from the first day to the seventh day
坐第一天坐到第七天他都不會走了
This is our different one
這是我們不一樣的一個
one by one one by one attitude
一個一個一個一個一個attitude
Nature also uses machine gun bags to indicate transfer
自然界也是用到機砲袋指示轉移
come and see
來我們來看
I give the simplest example
我舉個最簡單例子
same reason
一樣道理
this is called
這個叫做
it's flowering
這在花
There are many petals in the flower
花的花瓣裡面很多
You only need to see a little yellowish
你只要看到有一點點微黃
slightly yellowish
有一點點微黃
Basically something like this
基本上大概就是這個東西
then why this thing
那為什麼要這個東西
come and see
來我們來看看
This thing is less than 400 in Xiguang
這東西在西光是在小於400
is UV
就是UV
About 350 places
大概350的地方
can you watch
你可以看嘛
In fact, at 350
其實說在350
OK 400 has not absorbed for so long
OK 400這麼久沒有吸收
So everyone absorbs UV
所以UV地方大家都吸收
So as long as the sunlight is UV
所以只要太陽光是UV
it absorbs
它就吸收
After absorbing it, use a very fast speed, how fast?
吸收以後呢 用很快的速度 多快呢
OK, let's measure it first, about 60 DENTAL
OK 我們先測出來 大概60個FENTAL
It's as fast as -15 seconds at the 60th floor
就60層時的-15 次方秒 這麼快
Don't talk too fast, it will be right soon, OK
就不要講多快 就很快就對了 OK
come soon
就很快就過來
Come to this place, the same score is easy to pass, optimistic
過來這個地方呢 同分易過化 看好
When the light shines, it's very sour here, very sour Proton
一照光這邊很酸 很酸的Proton
Just come over to this Cabernell
就過到這個卡柏妮爾這邊過來
Then come to this place
然後就產這個同分易過化 到這個地方來
So in this Ground state
那所以說在這個Ground state的時候
it doesn't exist
它沒有存在
But it inspires attitude and it stabilizes
可是它激發態度它就很穩定下來
So when it shines it is very
所以放光的時候就是很
That energy level is very small
那個能階就很小
Probably in the green range OK
大概在綠色的範圍 OK
So you take UV
所以你照UV
Put it here quickly and then it turns green, what does it mean
很快放這邊 然後變成綠光 代表什麼意思
Isn't that the same as putting on sunscreen?
那就不跟你塗那個防曬油是一樣嗎
For you to wear sunscreen means
對 你塗防曬油就是說
Even the flowers are covered with sunscreen
就是花也塗了防曬油
OK after UV up
UV上去以後 OK
If you don’t put UV on, put some green light on it right away
UV不放UV 馬上就放什麼 放綠色的光
Why put green, it's fine if you don't emit light
為什麼放綠色 不放光就好了
Our sunscreen, I shine, no
我們防曬油我放光 沒有啊
why shine
為什麼要放光
Reabsorbed by Ye Lishu
又被葉利樹重新吸收
do it again
再重新做
Just look how smart that natural evolution is
你看那個自然演化就有多聰明
Right so natural evolution you have to believe how smart he really is
對不對 所以自然演化你就不得不相信他真的多聰明
so you look at this place in western state
所以你看他西州的這個地方
He shines for such a long time, what should the light normally be?
他放光在這麼長 一般放光應該是在什麼
next to this one in his west light
在他西光的這個旁邊
But he shines in such a long range
可是他放光在這麼長的範圍
Western State UV beams on green
西州UV放光在綠色的
Okay, I'll take this Kang and let it go today.
好 我今天就拿這個康放過來
Let's see one thing is
我們來看看一件事情是
fun thing
很好玩的一件事情
this
這個
Forget it, don't turn it off, let's take a look
算了 不用關了 我們看看
OK let's take a look at this
OK 我們來看看這個
Wait a minute, this can is what you see
先等一下 這一罐就是 你看
this is transparent all transparent
這是透明的 全部是透明的
As far as he is in UV, he has nothing at all
一就他西光都在UV 他根本沒有什麼
he just isn't visible
他就是沒有在 visible
If visible he has color
如果 visible 他有顏色啊
it's all transparent
這全部是透明的
If it is transparent first, let me see
如果先透明的話 我看看哦
I didn't fake it, it must be like this
我沒有做假啦 一定是這樣子
OK basically speaking
OK 基本上來講的話
I use UV light
我用 UV 光
But UV light?
可是 UV 光嘛
Yes it is UV light
對 是 UV 光
I use UV light you see
我用 UV 光照 你看哦
it's fully transparent
這是全透明的
OK so of course he is
OK 所以當然他就是
green
綠的
And it's green, it's green, it's green
而且很綠很綠很綠
OK basically
OK 基本上來講
he does it this way ok
他就用這種方式 OK
to take what
去把什麼
Metabolize these OK basically
把這些代謝掉 OK 基本上來講
So it's an interesting thought
所以這是很有趣的一個思維
I told you some
有跟各位講一些
That is to say, it actually has this function
就是說其實它有這種功能
Of course, we have many such applications in scientific research.
當然在科研上我們有很多這種應用了
I give the simplest application
我舉個最簡單的應用
In fact, this app is where you inspire this place
其實這個應用就是你激發這個地方
it's coming to this place soon
它馬上到這個地方來
Then it's slow after coming down
然後下來以後是慢的
Down is 10 - 9 is square seconds
下來都是10的-9是方秒
-15 of this 10 is square seconds
這10的-15是方秒
-9 out of 10 this is fast again
這10的-9這又很快
This is also 10-14-15
這也是10的-14-15
The representative said jump up
代表說蹦上去
Einstein told you about jumping up
阿因斯坦跟你講說蹦上去以後
Immediately spawn a bunch of
馬上就在這個地方產生一堆
A bunch with this place is no
一堆跟這個地方是沒有
produces the so-called population inversion
就產生所謂的population inversion
called G volume reversal
叫G量反轉
After the G quantity is reversed, the laser will come down immediately.
G量反轉以後這馬上就是雷射就下來
This is why we can see lasers
這是為什麼我們可以看到雷射
Of course I can't show it
我當然不能拿出來表演
you know my lab is down
你知道我實驗室就一倒
That laser comes out beautifully.
那個雷射就很漂亮就出來
So it's all lasers
所以這個都是雷射
Basically it's a great laser
基本上它是個很棒的雷射
let's take a look
我們再看一下
Is there any red one?
那有沒有紅色的呢
you said only green
你說只有綠色
Do you have others?
其他有沒有
Yes, you can give me an example
有啊 能夠隨便舉個例子
look at this kang fat
看 這個康胖
OK, this Kang Fat is the same
OK 這個康胖一樣啊
Can you see it?
這看得到吧
if you can't see look here
如果看不到看這邊
Because it's blocked below OK
因為這下面已經擋住了OK
So what can OH and N OK form
所以 OH跟N OK可以形成什麼
Form a Hydrogen Bump OK
形成一個Hydrogen Bump OK
So it's the same when it's illuminated
所以一照光以後一樣啊
this gets sour
這個變得很酸
Wherever you go, you have to go to this place
所有到哪裡去就要這個地方去
How fast? About 60 Fendals
多快呢 大概60個Fendal
What is the plural of 60 to 10?
60成10的複數是怎麼樣
Bump it in this place
Bump它在這個地方
Then down comes the red light
然後下來就是紅光
If you don't believe me, I'm going to show you this
如果怪不信來 我要用這個給你看
I am more beautiful, OK, let me take a look
我這更漂亮 OK 我看一看
Yes, I'll take a look
對 在不在 我看一看
should be in
應該是應該在
we are bullish
我們看好
This also needs to be transparent.
這個也需要透明的啊
OK you look transparent
OK 你看透明的
Then I will make UVU, this 360 will definitely work
然後我來製造UVU這360一定可以
red bright red
紅的 大紅
OK so you look beautiful OK
OK 所以你看就很漂亮 OK
Basically it's fine
基本上來講它沒有問題
Just use this way OK
就是用這種方式 OK
I put it here when I finish everything
我每個做完就放在這邊
Indicates that I am not cheating OK
表示我沒有作弊 OK
ok let's see
好 我們看一下
So one thing for everyone is
所以大家一件事情就是
you know what to say
你就知道說
it really is
它真的是這樣
ok say this
好 那說這個
What is this for
這個有什麼用
wait a minute i'll tell you
等一下我會跟你講說
There is a super useful place OK
有個超級有用的地方 OK
Everyone, if you listen to
各位如果聽一聽說
You can also go back and try
你也可以回去試試看
Green fluorescent protein also belongs to the type of direct transfer of G-Pythonite
綠色螢光蛋白也是屬於G-Pythonite 直直轉移的類型
why? ok let's see
為什麼?好我們來看
For example, this is a green fluorescent protein
譬如說這是綠色螢光蛋白的一個
a major luminophore
主要的一個發光團
What is this luminescent group actually related to?
這個發光團其實它是跟什麼
With H2O, with water, with Amino Acid
跟H2O 跟水 跟Amino Acid
It is Amino Acid Residue
就是Amino Acid Residue
what does it produce
它產生一個什麼
The so-called complex, a clean complex
所謂的一個complex 一個清淨的complex
So when you shine
所以你一照光以後
In fact, the H will drop
其實這個H就掉掉
It's so sour, just drop it
很痠嘛 就掉掉
Then go to this place to generate a massong relay called Massong Relay
然後到這地方產生一個我們叫做Massong Relay
This Proton is coming this way
這個Proton就到這邊來
So use something like this
所以用這樣的話
Actually it is a light
其實它是一照光
After this Proton is dropped
這個Proton掉掉以後
Synthesize it to produce a green glow
同分易購化它就產生一個綠色的發光
So what you see is a green glow
所以你看到的是一個綠色的發光
It's actually a Nion's glow
其實是個Nion的發光
basically you see a glow
基本上你看到一個發光
But then you pick it up
可是那完你把它拿起來
you can cut it off
你這個可以把它切掉
Because it's three Amino Acids that form this
因為這是三個Amino Acid形成的這個
after you take it off
你把它拿掉以後
It's like this when you pick it up
拿起來以後就這樣子
Take it up and shine it
拿起來以後一照光
nothing shines nothing nothing
什麼都沒放光 什麼都沒有
but the reason is simple
但原因很簡單
Because inside the protein, it's stuck
因為在蛋白質裡面,它是被卡死的
stuck in that place, it can't turn
卡死在那個地方,它沒辦法轉
nothing can be done
什麼都沒辦法
But after a bunch of them pick it up
可是一幫拿起來以後呢
Like a light, this place is called Vinyl's Glue
像一照光以後,這個地方叫做Vinyl的Glue
it keeps turning
它就一直轉
OK, so go up
OK,所以一上去
It was supposed to light up, but it kept spinning
本來要放光了,它一直轉
come down in this form
用這個形式就下來了
So it doesn't shine, it doesn't shine at all
所以它就不放光,完全不放光
You see, this quantum yield is a negative thing for a small moment
你看這個量子產力是小一時的負物
It means that there is nothing to say, and there is no light at all.
就代表說什麼都沒有,就根本不放光
OK, what about my lab?
OK,那在我的實驗室呢
It's very simple, you see how we do it
很簡單,你看我們怎麼做法
We have a very simple thinking
我們就很簡單的一個思維
OH in this place
OH在這個地方
I'll turn it around, turn it over to this place
我就把它轉,轉到這個地方來
Drawing is very simple, OK
畫是很簡單啦,OK
It is very difficult to learn to draw
畫學要做到很困難
Just move this OH over here
就把這OH把它移到這邊來
Let's see what it looks like when we move over here
我們看移到這邊變成什麼樣子
Wouldn't it be great if it became like this?
如果變成這樣子不是很好嗎
You see, if you change to OH and change to this place
你看變到OH變到這個地方的話
Originally in this place it will turn
本來在這個地方它會轉
But when there is a clear view here, it will not turn
可是這邊有清見以後它就不轉
It turns very little, it's not no turning, but very little turning
就轉得很少啦,不是不轉,而是轉得很少
OK, so of course it's possible
OK,所以當然是有沒有可能這樣
And when I shine, I don't need any water why
而且我一照光,我也不需要什麼水幹嘛
what it sees in itself
它內清見自己就會什麼
It will come and produce light
就會過來以後就產生放光
Is it possible like this?
有沒有可能這樣子呢
This is what we have done since 2007 and 2008
這就是我們從2007、2008年
there is a series
就有一系列
Probably all of them were developed in our laboratory.
大概全部都是我們實驗室發展出來
you see it is very simple
你看就很簡單
This is natural
這個本來是天然的
OK man-made we just put this OH
OK 人造了我們就把這個 OH
move over here
移到這邊來
OK once the light is on
OK 一照光以後
become what
就變成什麼
it can shine like that
它可以放光就跟剛剛那一樣
For example, we can use different substitution machines
譬如說我們可以用不同的取代機
in this place, in this place
在這個地方、這個地方
we can go all the way
我們可以從一路上
From yellow, orange, red
從黃色的、橘色的、紅色
Even to this unseen Neon Infrared
甚至到這個看不到的 Neon Infrared
OK can do this
OK 都可以這樣做
We are more powerful recently
我們最近更厲害就是
We don't think saying a Hide-Age Gold Rod is strong enough
我們認為說一個Hide-Age金棒不夠強
so what do we do
所以我們怎麼做呢
Let's just take this Hide-Age Gold Rod
我們就把這個Hide-Age金棒
LOG it for later
把它 LOG 住以後
Then use the above synthetic method
再把上面用合成的方式
LOG it again
再把它 LOG 住
If you see this place, put it in the LOG
你看這個地方就把它再把它 LOG 住
So after LOG live
所以 LOG 住以後
The two LOGs are called Double LOGs.
兩個 LOG 就我們叫 Double LOG 以後
camera hair
拍機發
You see, LASING will be produced immediately
你看 馬上就是產生 LASING
ok why
OK 為什麼
Because it emits strong light
因為它放光很強不強
So produce LASING immediately
所以就馬上產生 LASING
so very very beautiful
所以就非常非常漂亮
what i basically say
我基本上來講的話
OK so you see
OK 所以你就看到
When we shine light, a laser is emitted
我們一照光就產生雷射出來
But these two places you can tell it's lasers
但這兩個地方你就看出來是雷射
OK basically a beautiful experiment
OK 基本上就是很漂亮的一個實驗
OK of course you said
OK 當然你說
Yes, you synthesized this
是 你就是合成這個
and see if this is good
然後看看這個好不好
Of course not
當然不是啦
I use one please don't sleep
我用一張 拜託不要睡覺
I'll talk with one
我用一張就講
what the hell are we doing
我們到底在做什麼東西
actually what are we doing
其實我們在做什麼東西
we use
我們是用
Good, for example, our laboratory
看好 譬如說我們實驗室
OK with a 25 minute laser
OK 用一個25分鐘的雷射
OK 25 minutes is hard to do
OK 25分鐘是很難做的
If you are doing physics, you will know
在做如果有做物理的就知道
OK, what we can do in chemistry is not easy
OK 我們化學能做的就是不簡單
You see, after being stimulated
你看一激發上去以後
OK we are
OK 我們是
because it's fast
因為它很快
In fact, it is synchronized here
其實它同步在這個地方呢
resonate with each other
就產生互相共振
what do we call this
這個我們叫做什麼
called
叫做
called Ostration
叫做Ostration
That's it
就是這樣
we call
我們叫
Someone called Quantum Bit
有人叫做Quantum Bit
OK is the BitBitThing of Quantum
OK 就是量子的BitBitThing
OK then from here
OK 那從這個地方
This is because this is over time
這個因為這個是隨時間嘛
You can exchange time for
你把時間可以換成
frequency
頻率
OK so use
OK 所以用
After converting with Fullure
用Fullure轉換以後
you convert to a 120 WebNumber
你就轉換成一個120個WebNumber
This is its OverTone
這是它的OverTone
Just 120 WebNumber
就120個WebNumber
what does it mean
代表什麼意思
In fact, this thing
代表其實這個東西
How did the Program come here?
Program怎麼過來了
actually rely on what
其實都是靠什麼
rely on this
靠這個
One turn and pass
一彎以後就過去了
OK so a bend
OK 所以一彎
it vibrate
它就Vibrate
it goes by, so a vibration
它就過去,所以一個vibration
Just one vibration and it's gone
就一個振動它就過去了
Then you said that the same translation has changed here
那你說同分譯過化變在這裡
how do you know its structure
你怎麼知道它的structure
What are its molecules?
它的分子是什麼東西呢
Very simple, we also make a so-called
很簡單,我們也做一個所謂的
transient IR, this is more difficult to do
transient IR,這更難做了
Just make an IR, that is, after you type it up
就做一個什麼 IR,就是你打上去以後
then do another
然後再做一個
With an IR, within fintosecond
用一個IR的,在fintosecond之內
Just put it on the probe
就有把它probe上去
What can you get?
你就可以得到什麼呢?
You all get this is disappearing, this is generated
你都得到這個是消失的,這是生成的
So the generation is this keytone
所以生成就是這個keytone
This is the place that disappeared
消失的就是這個地方
so you know the generation disappears
所以你就知道生成消失
Indeed it has been synonymized
確實它有同分譯過化
In fact, we are doing these things
其實我們在做是做這些東西
Basically, it just shows you
基本上,它只是給你看
beautiful beautiful is in this place
漂亮漂亮的就是在這個地方
In fact, we do this thing
其實我們做做做這個東西
so you know it's my lab
所以你就知道這是我的實驗室
This is my real laboratory
這才是我的真正實驗室
Synthesize that, of course I also have
合成那個當然我也有
But basically my lab is like this
但是基本上我的實驗室大概就是這個
Anyway, it's all optics, so why?
反正全部都是光學,幹嘛幹嘛
If you don't believe me, those few
如果你各位不信的話,剛剛那個幾個
I also brought here
我這邊也帶來
basically just the weirdest
基本上剛剛最奇怪
These are different
這幾個就不同的
I can produce different colors
我可以產生不同顏色
For example, just this
比如說剛剛這個
like this
像這種
should be very red
應該是很紅
look
你看
very orange
橘很黃
So it just has to be
所以它就是一定是
There is Pronchance
有Pronchance
if you want red
如果你要紅的話
that means i'm cheating
這樣代表我作弊
put it here
放在這邊
won't fall
不會掉吧
Red is getting harder
紅的就越來越難了
cheat again
再作弊
Lingjian Village they know
凌健村他們知道
when you get redder
當你越紅的時候
the weaker the glow
發光就越弱
but also red
但是也是紅的
let's take a look
我們再看下來
just tell you one thing
就跟你講一件事情
If
如果說
any small piece
隨便一個小小的一塊
this place
這個地方
a lot of optics
光學一大堆
a lot of lenses
鏡片一大堆
per lens
每個鏡片
Probably less than 30,000
大概少說三萬吧
We spend about five or six million together
大家在一起大概就花五六百萬
basically
基本上來講
It cost about five or six million yuan just to change.
就進變大概有花了五六百萬以上
definitely above ok
絕對是以上的ok
So you know it costs nothing to say this
所以你就知道說這個其實所費不知
ok let's see
好我們看下來
that can just say
那剛剛可以講說
if today this is sour
如果今天這個很酸
it will come
它會過來
then you have an idea
那你就有一個想法
the idea is
這想法就
you can't control it
你不能去控制它的
mutual energy
互相的能量大小嗎
So actually I am in this 20
所以其實我在這個20
About 3 years ago 4 years ago
大概到3年前4年前
the idea is
這個想法就
just very very just
就非常非常就
can i control it
我能不能控制它
control it to
控制它到
It was one sided
到本來是一面倒的
ok can i turn it into yes
ok我可不可以把它變成是
It's a thing called equilibrium
它的是一個叫equilibrium
is that it is balanced
就是它是平衡
ok actually we were in 2011
ok其實我們在2011年
also make it really balance
也做出來它真的可以平衡
ok let's not talk more
ok我們就不多講
Just talk to you like this Kang Fat
只跟你講說像這個康胖
after a light
一照光以後
it can come here
它可以到這邊來
If you can also ventilate
也可以通風一過的話
it side
它這邊
via magnet transfer
經過磁石轉移
You can go here, you can go here
可以到這邊也可以到這邊
so you know
所以就知道說
one is 450
有一個是450
one is 600
有一個是600
Adding together is white light
加在一起就是白光
So we can also make white light out
所以我們也可以做出白光出來
So we are a single molecule
所以我們是一單一分子
can make a white light
可以做一個白光
not very efficient
效率不是很好
But last month when we
不過我們在上個月的時候
has developed another
已經又發展一個
wow that game is even better
哇 那個比賽更棒
OK
OK
That is pure white light
那個真是單純白光
Can reach more than 6%
可以達到6%以上
OK then I won't talk much
OK 那我就不多講了
OK because that hasn't been published yet
OK 因為那個現在還沒有發表
so i can't speak
所以我不能講
i can only say
我只可以講說
this is absolutely possible
這個是絕對是可以
You see, with this thing a single molecule
你看 用這種東西單一一個分子
I can do white light
我可以做白光
because of the ease of passing
因為通分易過化
OK basically
OK 基本上
it's a rare phenomenon
它這是一個很難得的現象
OK
OK
From this basic point of view
那從這個基礎的角度來講
what are we doing
我們在做什麼一樣東西呢
Actually, I have one that is challenging the Invasion Sword
其實我有一個在挑戰內侵劍
straight transfer limit
直直轉移的極限
what do you mean look
什麼意思 你看
Just talked about the first example
剛剛講第一個例子
This natural five
這個天然的五
this is the five rings
這是五圓環
i lose to you
我輸給你看
1 2 3 4 5
1 2 3 4 5
A total of five round papers constitute the Invasion Sword
總共是五個圓紙構成的內侵劍
That this red man just now
那這個剛剛那個紅人
is 1 2 3 4 5 6 6 rings
是1 2 3 4 5 6 6圓環
OK
OK
The six rings you can be OH and N
那六圓環你可以是OH跟N
You can also be N
你也可以是N
You can also be N and NH
你也可以是N跟NH
This is fine, the six rings
這個都可以 這個六圓環
OK
OK
Seven rings is what I just said
七圓環就是剛剛我講這個
So-called
所謂的
so-called fluorescent proteins
所謂的螢光蛋白質
move it OH over here
把它OH移到這邊
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven, the seven-membered ring
一二三四五六七這七元環
Let's talk about where the limit is
我們就講到底它極限在哪裡
So we spent a year
所以我們就花了一年的時間呢
This session is challenging and fun
這環節是挑戰好玩的
Basically we make eight-membered rings
基本上我們就做出八元環
The answer is, teacher, how do you do this?
那答案你說老師你這怎麼做
let me tell you okay
我跟你講好不好
In my laboratory is my design
在我實驗室就是我設計
I'll come over after I finish designing
我設計完以後過來
can this be done
這可不可以做
The answer says to start looking for basically
答案說開始找基本上
so you know i'm mistaken
所以你也知道我是誤化的
But I just talked to Vice President Wang
但是呢我剛才跟王副院長
I have a team dedicated to compositing
我有一個team就專門在做合成的
There are three post stars in charge of this thing
有三個post star在管這個東西
just do it
就專門做
I design can you do it
我設計你可不可以做
In the end, what we made was an eight-membered ring.
結果我們做出來的就是八元環
The eight-membered ring emits about 700
八元環就放光大概700
Already very weak very weak but it is there
已經很弱很弱但是它是有的
Is there a nine-membered ring?
有沒有九元環
In fact, I have already designed it and can't make it.
其實我已經設計了做不出來
Then see what you do along the way
那就一路上看你們辦法
a few rings
就做得到幾元環
it's an interesting thing
這是很有趣的一件事情
Now we're making eight-membered rings
現在我們在做八元環
The eight-membered ring should be the current limit.
八元環應該是目前的極限吧
basically
基本上
That's what I just said
那剛剛講的就是
Probably more OH
大概都是OH比較多
OK, is there any other Bounding recently?
OK 那有沒有其他的他最近Bounding 有啊
I just said that N is also okay, right?
剛剛講說N也可以啊 對不對
Then why is this important? You see, what we are developing now is more important.
那這個為什麼很重要 你看我們現在發展的這個更重要
What is the reason? Just now OH you also know that one O can only have two sticks
原因是什麼呢 剛剛OH你也知道一個O只能兩個棒
Right, but N is different
對不對 可是N不一樣啦
If there is an H on the N side, there is an H on this side, you can broaden your horizons
N這邊有個H的話 這邊有一個你可以海闊天空
to do so-called modification, chemical modification
去做所謂的修飾 化學修飾
This is important because NH2 is not acidic enough
這是很重要 因為NH2是不夠酸的
In fact, NH2 is a bit alkaline and not acidic enough.
其實NH2有一點鹼 不夠酸
So here we design a pull electron
所以我們這邊就設計一個拉電子
OK pull very strongly, such as Tosio Group
OK 很強力拉 譬如Tosio Group
Let's not talk too much, just like this group
我們就不多講 就是像這個Group
OK is a SOO
OK 就是一個SOO
Like this, this, if this pulls electrons very strongly
像這樣 這樣 這個拉電子很強的話
After pulling this, what can this place do? It's sour.
這個一拉以後呢 這個地方就可以什麼 很酸
it can do direct transfer
它就可以做直直轉移
So you see we use chemical modification to modify it and we can do it
所以你看我們用化學修飾 把它修飾就可以做
OK basically speaking so you know what to say
OK 基本上來講的話 所以你就知道說
How sour or not sour are we doing this way
我們用這種方式 到底有多酸或不酸
Why, why, why, we can tune it to connect with each other
幹嘛幹嘛幹嘛 我們可以Tune它互相的能結
What can we tune in now? It’s the same as before
我們現在可以Tune到什麼呢 一樣到底跟剛剛一樣
Better yet, we're rationalizing Tune to white light
更棒是我們是合理化Tune到白光
So in this way you hear the white light
所以用這種方式就聽到白光
This combines synthetic
這就結合了合成物化
everything together and apply
所有東西在一起還要應用
So definitely something to do in this place
所以在這地方絕對是可以做的
It can be said that chemistry is actually a family.
這就可以講說化學其實都是一家嘛
It's up to you how to interpret it
看你要怎麼去解讀它而已
Basically it's one thing you can do
基本上來講這是可以做的一件事情
I give an example
我舉一個例子
This example lets you examine
這例子讓你審視一下
what am i doing now
我現在在做什麼東西
because of course since
因為當然是自從
After the National Science Council is changed to the Ministry of Science and Technology, you have to do some applications
國科會改成科技部以後你也不得不做一些應用
Otherwise you will be KO basically speaking
要不然你會被KO基本上來講的話
Then let me tell you about an application
那我來跟你講一個應用
it's fun
很好玩喔
what is this application
這應用是什麼東西
we look at one thing
我們看一件事情
if today
假如今天
The screen we're looking at
我們看的這個螢幕
This screen is called the absorption screen
這螢幕叫做吸收螢幕
Keep playing a color and let you see the color over there
一直打一個顏色出來在那邊顏色讓你看到
right
對不對
If you imagine this screen
如果想像說這個螢幕
is transparent
是透明的
transparent
透明的
But there is RGB inside
可是裡面有RGB
There are Blue and Green and Red
就是有Blue跟Green跟Red
The dye is in three layers
的染料在三層
OK
OK
and then yours
然後呢你的
your this
你的這個
Where's your projector?
你的這個投影機呢
actually every color in it
實際上是每一個顏色在裡面
When you load your picture into it
當你把loading你的圖進去的時候
it came out
它出來了
according to the diagram
按照圖
In fact, there are three UV light
實際上是有三個UV的光
This UV light is invisible
這UV光是看不到的
call here
打到這個地方來
A light hit is for you blue
一個光打是給你藍色
one light hit one green
一個光打一個綠色
a light to red
一個光打給紅色
OK
OK
you regulate according to this
你根據這樣調控
you know what to say
你就知道說
In this way, it is a full-color
這樣這樣出來就是一個全彩
Full color transparent screen
叫全彩透明螢幕
Now it's the hottest
現在是最夯最夯的
OK basically speaking
OK 基本上來講的話
is completely transparent
就完全是透明的
but now do so far
可是現在做到目前為止
no
不行
what is the reason
原因是什麼
They all use fluorescent powder
他們都是用螢光粉
Phosphor powder is very unhappy
螢光粉怎麼做都非常不樂
very blurred
就非常的模糊化
OK
OK
basic
基本
Now the most famous is the inside of the car
現在最有名的就是汽車裡面的
look inside this car
你看這汽車裡面
On top of this Winds Shear
在這個Winds Shear上面
Whatever the light-shielding glass is for?
隨便這個擋光玻璃幹嘛上面的
These
這些
OK
OK
is above
就是上面
right here there is one like this
就這邊有一個像這樣
There is a Project
有一個Project
This Project is a Project
這Project是Project
you see it's all green
你看它都是綠色
Why else is it red?
要不然是紅色幹嘛
It can't do full color
它做全彩沒辦法
Because technically it doesn't work
因為技術上是行不通的
OK technically it doesn't work
OK 技術上是行不通
Why
為什麼
very simple
很簡單
If you don't show it
你這個不露的話
You call Blue, will Blue get Red in this place?
你打Blue,Blue到這個地方會不會Red?
meeting
會
Why? Because you have Red means there will be in Blue
為什麼?因為你有Red就表示會有在Blue
So you can never get past this level
所以你永遠沒辦法去過這一層
How do you get past this level? Can’t you just talk about it?
你怎麼過這一層?剛剛不可以講嗎?
Inward direct transfer is absolutely possible
內直直轉移絕對是可以的
Why? Because the direct transfer is released by Cyub in the place of Red and Green
為什麼?因為直直轉移是Cyub放出是在Red,Green這個地方
So I know where to go to find my inner light
所以我知道在這個地方去找我的內直直轉移放光強的
Then blue is enough to use ordinary blue
然後Blue就用普通的Blue就夠了
too much, ok
太多了,OK
Then this place you see when I fire up in Red
然後這個地方你看我激發在Red的時候
This place I get is such a long wavelength
這個地方我得到是這麼長的波長
Right when it was Green I got to be in this place
就在Green的時候我得到是在這個地方
So this place is not absorbed, so just bypass
所以這個地方都沒有吸收,所以就bypass
i can see three
我就可以看到三個
Well, if you don't believe me, I just put these two in
好,如果你不信的話,我剛剛把這兩個放進來
OK, put three layers, you can't see the three layers, but it's transparent
OK,放三層,這你看不到三層,可是透明的
OK, take a look
OK,你看看喔
I know 380 is Green
我知道380是Green
To 400, this color is not good, OK, it should be Red
到400,這個顏色不好,OK,應該是Red
to 420 is Blue
到420是Blue
You see, long wavelengths get short wavelengths
你看,長波長得到短波長
Yes, long wavelengths get long wavelengths
對,長波長得到長波長
Cutting these three together is white light
這三個砍在一起就是白光
OK so don't underestimate it
OK 所以不要小看喔
Maybe I will be the billionaire chairman in the future
搞不好我將來是幾十億的董事長
OK this could be
OK 這有可能是
just tell you look
就跟你講說 你看
This is a basic science
這就是一個basic science
But he can use it
可是他可以活用啊
he can definitely use it
他絕對可以活用
just tell you the truth
就跟你講說其實
actually i tell you
其實我跟你講
fondamento is really important
fondamento真的很重要
OK we're just fondamento
OK 我們只是fondamento
not this far
沒有到這個地步
so everyone said
所以大家又說
ah why do what
啊 幹嘛幹嘛幹嘛
you just have to get to a certain point
你只要能到某個地步
In fact, you must be rich
其實你一定是一本萬利的
In fact, we have not reached this point
其實我們更沒有到這個地步
So it's always stuck in this place
所以永遠就是卡在這個地方
okay, let me tell you
好不好 我這跟各位講
it might be ok
這有可能OK
then don't forget
那不要忘了
Just that grape palm tree
剛剛那個葡萄棕樹
What are these things for?
這些東西幹嘛
Hey, it took more than twenty years
欸 花了二十幾年了
right not two months
對不對 不是兩個月
not two years
不是兩年了
right so of course
對不對 所以當然是
ok let's see
好 我們看喔
the shift that inspires here
那激發在此的轉移
intermolecular
也可以在分子間進行
I give an example
我舉個例子
Just started with five-membered rings
剛剛是從五元環開始
It is impossible to make a gold rod with a four-membered ring
四元環就不可能還做金棒
Right, four-membered ring one two three four is impossible
對不對 四元環一 二 三 四就不可能
Impossible to say this H and Z
不可能說這個H跟 Z
Because of four impossible things
因為四個這不可能的事情啊
how it was formed and made a gold rod
它怎麼形成還做金棒
Hey let's see
欸 我們看
It's between Dimer and it's double
它就介於Dimer 就是雙挺
right this and this
對不對 這個跟這個
You can also see
你看也可以啊
I won't show once I'm excited, I'll tell you
一激發以後我就不秀,我跟你們講
Once activated, this Proton can come over
一激發以後這個Proton可以過來
This Proton can come
這個Proton可以過來
Two, we call them Double Proton Transmitter
兩個,我們叫做Double Proton Transmitter
Just switch two Protons together
就兩個Proton一起Switch
what green light you can get too
你也可以得到什麼綠色光
OK, so why is the Study so hard?
OK,那為什麼Study這個都這麼夯?
did that just tell you
那剛剛已經跟你講過嘛
look at some of our examples
你看看我們幾個例子
Let's take a look at the knowledge transfer in the DNA clipping team
我們看看說,知識轉移在DNA剪輯隊中
Can it happen? And entry produces mutations
可以發生嗎?而進入產生突變
This is 40 years, 50 years
這是40年來、50年來
Wasn't and Click from this Wasn't
從這個Wasn't開始的Wasn't跟Click
everyone is discussing this
大家在討論這件事情
OK, is it possible to mutate
OK,說有沒有可能突變
Because these two Proton
因為這兩個Proton
OK, these two Protons
OK,這兩個Proton
After hearing this, these two Double Proton
這個聽見以後這兩個Double Proton
When Proton comes with Switch, it needs to be flexible and easy to buy.
Proton一Switch過來,要變通分易購化以後
Then start copying at this place
然後在這個地方開始開始開始複製的話
there is a copy error
就有複製錯了
Actually this Wasn't the first to bring it up
其實這是Wasn't第一個提出來
He said is it possible that
他說有沒有可能這種情形
OK, that's easy from here
OK,那從這個地方很簡單
We want Study to say
我們要Study說
Is it possible that after the light is
照光以後有沒有可能是
Let the two ProtonSwitch
讓這兩個ProtonSwitch
OK, generate Mutation
OK,產生Mutation
This is also me in 1990
這也是我在1990年
to 19 in about 2001, what about these 10 years
到19大概在2001年,這10年呢
My focus is very strong in this place
這個地方我focus很強很強
I spend almost half of my manpower on this place
我幾乎把一半的人力都花在這個地方
Because there were fewer people at that time
因為那個時候人比較少
But half of the people spent in this place
但一半人一花在這個地方
It's a pity to tell you no
很可惜的跟你講說不行
you see why not
你看為什麼不行
I can tell the simplest truth now
我現在可以講一個最簡單的道理
after you shine
你照光以後
If you say this proteon is going to pass
如果你說這個proteon要過去
This proteon is coming
這個proteon要過來
I'm sorry that this synonym is too much
很抱歉是這個同分義過化
This is also synonymous
這個也同分義過化
Two synonymous transition energy is too high
兩個一起同分義過化能量太高
impossible
不可能
so why do i know
那為什麼我知道這樣子
Because what do we do, it won't work, right?
因為我們怎麼做不行對不對
But let's take a very simple acid touch
可是我們就拿一個很簡單的觸酸
We stuck acid in this place
我們把觸酸卡在這個地方
If you get stuck at Adning
卡在Adning這個地方的話
Contact acid can be used to form Diamond
觸酸可以來形成Diamond
How do you know it's a Diamond
你怎麼知道成Diamond
Because it can be seen from the absorption
因為從吸收可以看出來
I won't draw it
我就不畫出來
It forms a Diamond with my light
它形成Diamond有我一照光
it produces a green glow
它產生了綠色的放光
And red or green shine
而且紅的還是綠色的放光
just tell you one thing is
就跟你講一件事情是
In fact, this can be proteon switch
其實這個是可以proteon switch的
no problem
沒有問題
Then, teacher, what is the difference between here and here?
那說老師這跟這裡什麼不同
Where is the difference
哪裡不同
You see, this is the change of both
你看這個是兩個都要變
This is the subject is the subject, anyway both will change
這是主體才是課題 反正兩個都要變
But what about this, if this is the subject of the project?
可是這個呢 如果這是課題這主體的話
The main body has changed, has the topic changed or not?
主體變了課題有沒有變 沒變
Why because COH is still COH
為什麼 因為COH還是COH
OK, I didn’t name this one Catalytic Time
OK 這個我就沒有命名叫Catalytic Time
Actually when I sent out the first one in 1999
其實我第一個在1999年發出去的時候
Oh, what about that Propel Jax
喔 那個這個Propel Jax的話
Come back in a week and say incredible
一個禮拜就回來說 不可思議
how do you think of such a thing
你怎麼想到這種事情
Ah, this is, ah, why do you keep talking about 1999?
啊這個就是 啊你說為什麼會一直講1999
OK someone over here should know
OK 有人在這邊應該知道
Because there were no instruments at that time
因為那時候什麼儀器都沒有
And why not after a while because of the big earthquake
而且一會兒就為什麼沒有 因為大地震
In Chung Cheng University OK later the instrument was burned
在中正大學 OK 後來儀器被燒掉了
So there is nothing, nothing depends on the brain
所以什麼都沒有 什麼沒有就靠腦筋啊
Just us, you have nothing to do, just rely on your brain
就我們 你什麼都沒有就怎麼辦 就靠腦筋嘛
OK, just think about these things in your head, it's not healthy
OK 靠腦筋就想這些 不康無順的
Let's see if it's possible, right? No need for instruments.
就看看有沒有可能 對不對 也不用儀器啊
You can still do it so I'll tell you
你還是做得出來啊 所以我就跟你講說
Rely on your brain when you have no money
當你沒錢的時候就靠腦子嘛
OK, your brain will always figure it out
OK 你腦子總會想出來啊
Of course, what Dean Wang said is correct, because I am a workaholic
當然王院長講的一句話是對的 因為我是工作狂
So basically I can't learn it, just thinking here OK
所以基本上我也學不下來 就在這邊想 OK
You see, after the big earthquake
你看說大地震以後
More than a year, published three consecutive days OK
一年多 連續發表三天 OK
Everything is the simplest concept
全部都是最簡單的 的概念
I didn't lie to you, it's just a concept
我沒有騙你,就是概念而已
Nothing to do, just do the simplest things like this
什麼都沒有做,就做做這種最簡單的東西
OK, so we're going to call it Catalyst type
OK,所以我們要叫做Catalyst type
OK, that's the catalyst, because it doesn't move
OK,就是這是催化,因為它不動
This is not called catalysis, so it won't work
這個不叫催化,所以它不行
it's that simple
就這麼簡單一件事情
ok , then i will give you a better example
好,那我再給你一個更好例子
Let's start from here
我們從這個地方去開始衍生
How to derive it? You see
怎麼衍生呢?你看
we derive, for example, we synthesize
我們就衍生,譬如說我們就合成
You said that the synthesis is not difficult, not difficult
你說合成這個困不困難,不困難
Because he has already synthesized it, but he doesn't want to do it
因為人家已經合成過了,可是他不想要幹嘛
OK, I'll do it from this place, ah, it works
OK,我從這個地方去做,啊,它有用
Why is it useful, you see this place for the same reason
為什麼有用,你看這個地方一樣道理
You see, Acoho or water words
你看,Acoho或水的話
If it's Acoho water, you see
如果是Acoho水,你看
If this stuck in this place, a fire
如果這個卡在這個地方,一激發
It's still the same, Acoho is still Acoho, but this will change
它還是一樣,Acoho還是Acoho啊,可是這個會變啊
OK, if that's the case
OK,如果是這樣的話
Because people dropped him from this Urea
因為人家是把他就掉這個Urea
They are synthesized to remove Urea's derivatives
人家是合成出來去掉Urea的衍生物
I said, ah, how to do this
我說,啊,怎麼這樣做
This is obviously in Acoho water
這個明明是在Acoho水裡面呢
It should be easy to buy
它應該是會通分易購化
Because both will change
因為這個兩個都要變
So it won't, so it should be no entry
所以它不會,所以這應該是不入
This should be Rate
這應該是Rate
in organic people do this stuff
在有機的人去做這種東西
just watch normal MMA
只是看普通MMA
Just take a look, right?
看一看就算了,對不對
This should be Blue, this should be Rate
這個應該是Blue,這應該是Rate
Is there such a possibility?
有沒有這種可能性呢?
I say learn to synthesize
我就說學成合成
OK, this is not a very difficult thing
OK,這並不是很困難的一件事情
So they start to synthesize
所以他們就開始合成
After the synthesis is completed, you can see
那合成完以後,你看喔
but we added a group
但我們加了一個group
We added a COO group
我們加了一個COO group
Why? Because it is better to make it water soluble
為什麼?因為要讓它水溶性要好
OK, look, in the water
OK,你看,在水裡面
so my consciousness is right
所以我的意識是對的
My consciousness, well, my consciousness can just talk
我的意識,欸,我的意識只是可以講說
I am better than people without this knowledge
我比沒有這方面知識的人
It's 10 times more likely, that's all I am
就多10倍的可能性,我就這樣子而已
As long as the chance of winning is 10 times, or 100 times, that's all
就中獎機率是多10倍,或100倍就這樣子而已
OK, I can’t say they’re all right, if you can’t make them all, then you can’t
OK,我不能說全對,都做出來不行就不行
I can't help it either
我也沒辦法
OK, but like this
OK,但是這樣子
OK, let's force it in later
好,我們把它加有力的進去以後
look what it looks like
你看變什麼樣子
After the card is in, eh, it’s gone
卡進去以後,欸,就沒有了
Yes, so this is a RUN concept
對,所以這個就是一個RUN概念
nothing
什麼也不用啊
Hey, let me tell you, okay?
欸,我跟你講好不好
I didn't even measure the spectrum.
這個連光譜都沒有測喔
Just take one photo, and there is no equipment
就照一個,又沒有儀器啊
Just shine like this, shine like this
就照光這樣照光這樣
Super published, OK, basically speaking
超強發表,OK,基本上來講
It's just a matter of concept, it's an obvious thing
就是概念的問題嘛,這很明顯的一件事情
Tell me, hey, it works
講說,欸,它是可以通的喔
ok we'll be back
好,我們再回來
This just this India
這個剛剛這個印度
Yes, Morigata Ajaw, this place in India
對 森方阿爪印度這個地方
Didn't you just say that Dimer is okay?
剛剛不是說Dimer可以嗎
Well if Dimer can
那如果Dimer可以的話
That can also be done in Ako
那在Ako裡面也可以
Of course not wrong
當然沒有錯
Look inside Ako
在Ako裡面 看喔
this is in
這個在
This time in Cyco Accent in that Langpora
這個次在Cyco Accent 在那個Langpora裡面
There is no software in Proton
沒有Proton的Software裡面
it is a light
它就是一個放光
But in Ako there are only two lights
可是在Ako裡面就是兩個放光
what is this
這個就是什麼
This is the oversynthesis of it
這個就是它同分義過化啦
Make a catalytic reaction from this place
從這個地方做一個催化反應
come this way
這樣過到這邊來
OK good
OK 好
don't do a magic trick in this place
在這個地方不要一個魔術
look at this
這個你看喔
this is more fun
這個更好玩
This place has Ako
這個地方有Ako
so i am
所以我在
I casually
我隨便
Come on, let's take this example
來 我們去取個這個例子
Look, this bottle is
看喔 這一瓶就是
It's also transparent, right?
也是透明的對不對
Habits of transparency
習慣透明
This might turn off the lights
這個可能要關燈一下
wait a minute
等一下 等一下
OK look
OK 看喔
Then this time in Cyco Accent
那這個次在Cyco Accent裡面
I know a little bit of Ako
我知道有一點Ako
Super Sensitive
超級Sensitive
Era-6M Lipstick
時代-6M的儀唇
it becomes like this
它就變這樣子啊
It is OK that it combines super strong
就是它結合力超強的OK
basically
基本上來講
so let's see
所以我們來看看
The answer is how it looks OK
答案是怎麼樣子OK
what about this
那這個呢
as soon as you shine
你一照光以後
OK this
OK 這個
After you shine on the light, you basically talk
你一照光以後基本上來講的話
it is probably
它就是大概
no
就沒有
Why? Because it shines at 360, 350, can't see
為什麼?因為它放光在360、350,看不到
OK, you can't see, basically
OK,你就看不到,基本上
good
好,看好
I'm doing a show now
我現在做一個表演
I haven't moved this can, don't say I cheated, I'll take a look
我這罐沒有動,不要說我作弊,我看看
what is this ? beer
這是什麼?啤酒
I put this can here
我這罐放在這邊
i open the beer
我把啤酒打開
Can't drink, can't open, can't open
不會喝酒,不會打開,打不開
hold on , ok , look on
等一下,好,看好
I didn't paint it
我沒有塗喔
ok ok ok enough , enough of the booze
好,好,夠了,酒脆夠了
it should be soon, ok
這應該很快啦,OK
Because of chemistry, this saves unlimited Diffusion Control
因為化學這種省無限的Diffusion Control
It's all coming soon, look
都很快了,看好
fast enough, ok
夠快了吧,OK
Question 16, 16M, whatever you do
問題16,16M,你不管怎麼樣
You said that when you pass the place where the tide is drunk, you will be killed
你說經過酒潮地方,你就會被
Detecting alcohol trucks, it's impossible
檢測酒車,這是不可能發生的事情
So this is free, OK
所以這個就免啦,OK
and it breaks so it doesn't work
而且它會摔破,所以就不好用
but it can
但是它確實是可以
no problem at all
一點問題都沒有
A lot of fun
很好玩
Okay, more exciting next time, let's take a look
好 接下來更精彩 我們看下來
So the single thing is
所以單一件事情是
If you use this structure
如果用這個架構
What about the water?
你說那水呢
just arco
剛剛是arco
water
水呢
As soon as we look like water, we'll be fine.
我們一看起來是水一定可以
water is not good
水不行
glow of water
水的放光
This absorbing light is right here
這吸收放光就在這邊
without this pack
沒有這一包
This package is only available in arco
這只在arco裡面才有這一包
why not water
說水為什麼不行
I'll tell you one thing why not
我就跟你講一件事情為什麼不行
in the water
在水裡面
no matter what
不管怎麼樣
Because of acidity and alkalinity
因為有酸鹼性的問題
Everyone knows this NH
這個NH大家都知道
blood flow know
血化血流知道
The NH of this steak in this NH is not sour
這個NH的這個排肉的NH是不酸的
OK
OK
so how to say
所以怎麼講
butyric acid
酪酸
When the H drops and changes to this side
當這個H掉掉變到這邊來了以後
what this becomes
這個就變成什麼
Weak acid is strong
弱酸就強減
so im sorry
所以強減抱歉
When I was waiting for the first phase of PH
在PH等一期的時候
It Protonate Immediately
它馬上就Protonate
so it doesn't shine
所以它就不放光
there is nothing you can do
你一點辦法都沒有
what can you turn it into
你一點辦法把它變成什麼
turn it into
把它變成
This place makes it a bit more acidic
這個地方把它變成強酸一點
Its resistance is always weakened
它的抗拒有就是弱減
it's possible in the water
在水裡面就可能
Look, I just thought of this concept, right?
你看我只想到這個概念對不對
Chemistry is just like that, right?
化學就這樣子而已嘛對不對
So how do you turn it into a stronger acid
所以怎麼把它變成比較強的酸
not easy
還不簡單
You can do whatever you want, as long as Mr. Lin comes over and say
你可以隨便我只要在林老師過來說
At that time you just didn't design
你那時候你只不設計
It's simple, just pull the electron
簡單嘛就拉電子就好啦
It is more acidic to design a pull electron
設計個拉電子它就比較酸
Let's design a pull electron
我們就設計個拉電子
It will be more acidic for the design to pull electrons
對設計個拉電子它就會比較酸
Sour its conjugate and it will become dissolved
酸它的conjugate就變成落解嘛
it will not be protonin
它就不會被protonin
Is the answer like this?
答案是不是這樣子呢
The answer is really like this
答案真的是這樣子
OK this is totally OK to sell the concept
OK這完全是賣概念的OK
So what was published at that time
所以那時候發表的都是什麼
two pages per page
兩頁一頁
Anyway, it’s OK to sell concepts
反正就是賣概念就OK
Just look at it and add a CA.
就是你看就是加個CA出來啦
It was only this
本來是只有這個
this is what
這個就是一個什麼
it's this one that shines like this
它就是這個會放光就這樣子
such a simple thing
這麼簡單的一件事情
OK, I won't talk about this
好啊這個我就不講了
It's okay for you to sleep when you talk about this
這個講起來你們就睡覺OK
just tell you if it will be like this
就跟你講說它會不會這樣子
OK basically
OK基本上來講
How about this project?
好這個project呢
Since I came to National Taiwan University
自從我來的去台大以後
Wang Yifu gave a speech just now. I went there in 2001
剛剛王一夫演講我2001年去的
OK to go basically
去的OK基本上
What about since 2002?
那從2002年呢
because
因為
all the materials
所有的材料當道
OK so the answer is
OK 所以答案是
From 2002 to 2008
從2002到2008
I'm out of my research focus
我就out of my research focus
What about adding
講什麼adding
what indole group
什麼indole group
I will stop
我就停啦
I'll switch lanes
我就轉換跑道
OK actually I posted on TV Shine
OK 其實我發表在電視發光
With the new generation of solar cells
跟新世代太陽電池的
Paypal is too much
paypal超多了
OK basically I won't talk today
OK 基本上 我今天都不講
OK basically speaking
OK 基本上來講的話
i think some people know ok
我想有些人知道 OK
So the answer is to switch the direction
所以答案就是轉換了這個方向
But I will not talk about this direction today
可是我今天不講這個方向
what am i going to say
我要講什麼呢
OK because after 2009
OK 因為2009年以後呢
I restarted this
我重新又啟動這個
why start this thing
為什麼要啟動這個東西
Because
原因是
What about 2009?
2009年呢
I set up a program called
我就成立了一個叫做
poster-glanding team
poster-glanding team
Wow this sounds very
哇 這個聽起來就是很
It seems that men's things are OK
好像男人的東西OK
It's the social affairs team
就是社務線小組
OK, is it not me?
OK 可可不是我聽問
But the members of the social affairs line group said
可是社務線小組裡面成員說
two female teachers
兩個女老師
OK so full of embarrassment
OK 所以滿尷尬的
basically
基本上
Then why is it called the Social Affairs Line Group?
那為什麼叫社務線小組
Because we are studying the social affairs line
因為我們在研究社務線的
of this
的這個
It is poster-glanding
就是poster-glanding
Just poster-glanding this
就poster-glanding這個
The mechanism of this synthesis
這個合成的機制
OK, let me give you a few examples.
OK 譬如說我幾個例子啊
let's see
我們看啊
This is the so-called poster-glanding
這個是所謂的poster-glanding
This is it
就是這個
How did PGH2 come about?
PGH2 怎麼來的
from fatty acids
就是從脂肪酸
OK after Cyclooxygenase
OK 經過 Cyclooxygenase
After OK and Poxidase
OK 跟 Poxidase 以後呢
It's over here by Poxidase
它就在這邊被Poxidase
then after
然後經過
only two two
只有兩個 兩道
One is Pgis which is antithrombin
一個是 Pgis 就是抗凝血酶
OK one is Somboxxan Sinceres
OK 一個就是 Somboxxan Sinceres
thrombin
就是凝血酶
These two are checks and balances
這兩個是互相制衡的
checks and balances
互相制衡
I give an example
我舉個例子
for example
譬如說
You are hurt
你受傷了
There are a bunch of these in the platelets
在血小板裡面就一堆的這些
thrombin
凝血酶
why
為什麼呢
because it will be what
因為它就會什麼
Immediately blown into blood acid
馬上吹化成是血酸素
what makes you condense
讓你什麼凝結
OK if you have a heart block
OK 如果你是心臟堵塞了
or why
或幹嘛幹嘛
you need to pass
你需要通
OK is antithrombin
OK 就是抗凝血酶
To this side, it becomes the front row ring number
到這邊就變成前列環數
then let you what
然後讓你什麼
let you this place is accessible
讓你這個地方是可以通的
So these two are checks and balances
所以這兩個是互相制衡
over here
這邊呢
in fact to be honest
事實上老實講
Even X-ray knows
就是 X-ray 都知道
OK this
OK 這個
the antithrombin
這個抗凝血酶
Its structure is known
它的 structure 都知道
I don't know this place
這個地方不曉得
why don't you know
為什麼不曉得
Because of its large active center
因為它的活性中心超大的
So I can't get my body out
所以結不出經體出來
I know that felt from National Taiwan University
我知道那個台大的那個氈
what felt
什麼氈
Where is felt
氈哪裡
OK I've been trying to get it but I can't
OK 一直想去結不出來
OK basically
OK 基本上來講
so this place is
所以這個地方是
it has its
它有它的
its place as
它的可以作為的地方
we are researching this place
我們在研究這個地方
After all because it all belongs to Satocon P450
到底因為這都屬於Satocon P450
There is HIM and that straight
就是有HIM 有那個直直
so straight up
所以在直直上面
We can use Lyman spectroscopy to study that
我們就可以用萊曼光譜去研究說
How did it change after it entered?
它進去以後到底是怎麼變化幹嘛
we will study this
我們就研究這方面
That's because it's related to Poscagetin
那因為是跟Poscagetin有關係
related to color wireless
跟色無線有關係
Let's ask the color wireless team
我們請問一下色無線小組
you know
各位你也知道
What do you want to relieve the pain?
你說要什麼止痛幹嘛
Everyone use the rainy forehead below to relieve the pain
大家都把下面的下雨額去止痛
Everyone knows the best pain reliever
最棒的止痛大家都知道
If you go to the hospital and say I'm dying of pain
如果你去醫院說我痛得快死掉
I'll tell you about the hospital
我跟你講那個醫院
If the doctor said you could die
那個醫生說管你去死的話
Just give you cox
就是給你cox就好啦
Inhibitor for you cox
給你cox的inhibitor
block this place
把這個地方阻塞掉
Make sure you don't have any pain
保證你什麼痛都沒有
you take one without pain
你拿一個痛都沒有
Basically this is the most upstream
基本上這是最上游的
so you see that you say cox
所以你看那個你說cox
like every time i go to say give me a cox inhibitor
像我每次去說給我一個cox的inhibitor
After this time, I guarantee you will have no pain at all
這一次以後保證你什麼痛都沒有
basically
基本上來講
Then why is there no pain? It’s not good anymore
那什麼痛沒有已經並不好
Because of your natural disaster or something
因為你的天然災害什麼東西
You don't even know what your body is doing
你身體幹嘛你就都不曉得
let me tell you first we have this
我先跟你講說我們有這個
you say this to me
你說這個跟我
Because what did I have to do with it just now?
因為我剛剛上面有什麼關係呢
has a lot to do with
有很大關係
OK, let's study these two
OK 那我們就研究這兩個的
OK it all belongs to P
OK 它都屬於P
That Satocon P450's
那個Satocon P450的
Just have a Sorayband
就是有一個Sorayband
Because it has Porphine
因為它有Porphine
straight this place
直直的這個地方
In fact, we have studied a lot of Raman
其實我們有研究很多的Raman
I won't talk about it, I won't talk about it
我就不多講這個我不講
Let me tell you about the Raman spectrum
我跟你講Raman光譜
When this sub-save comes in
當這個sub-save進來以後
OK its spectrum changes
OK 它的光譜的變化
changes over time
隨著時間的變化
OK let's study it
OK 我們去研究它的
its Lyman spectrum
它的來曼光譜
just these things
剛剛的這些東西
OK then this is not important
OK 那這個不重要
the most important thing is
最重要的一件事情是
when we study this
當我們去研究這個
When Somboxan Synthesis
Somboxan Synthesis的時候
OK we just found out one thing
OK 我們就發覺一件事情
A lot of fun
很好玩
It has a total of five Trip Open
它總共有五個Trip Open
There are always five Trip Opens in it
它這裡面總有五個Trip Open
What about these five Trip Opens?
這五個Trip Open呢
Just five tryptophan five tryptophan
就五個色安酸 五個色安酸
What about the five cromotropins?
這五個色安酸呢
Basically it's 1 2
基本上來講是1 2
W means Trip Open OK
W就是Trip Open OK
This student's pictorial text is clearer than me OK
這個學生畫文是比我更清楚 OK
1 2 3 4 5
1 2 3 4 5
These five Trip Open
這五個Trip Open
What about these five Trip Opens?
這五個Trip Open呢
One thing that can obviously be said is
很明顯可以講一件事情是
When we use these just this
當我們用這些剛剛這個
What is Laman Spectrum doing?
來曼光譜幹嘛幹嘛
we already know that
我們已經知道說
Actually, what about the four blue places?
其實這四個藍色地方呢
is very polar
是極性很強的
This place is practically almost non-polar
這個地方實際上是幾乎沒有極性
We know it has almost no polarity
我們知道它幾乎沒有極性
OK
OK
We use various spectra
我們用各種的光譜
We all know this has no polarity
我們都知道這個沒有極性
but we don't know
可是我們不曉得
What is the reason for this lack of polarity?
這個沒有極性到底是因為什麼
because there is no water or nothing
因為是沒有水還是沒有什麼東西
no X-ray
沒有X-ray
X-ray is useless
有X-ray沒有用
X-ray to see water
X-ray看水
Teacher Wang knows that looking at the water is useless
王老師就知道看水沒有用啊
OK so everyone one thing is
OK 所以大家一件事情是
We know this W65 is here
我們知道這個W65在這裡
Then, when Postakening came in like this
然後呢那個Postakening這樣進來的時候
When PGH2 came in like this
就PGH2這樣進來的時候
actually it's still passing here
實際上它還在經過這裡
That's a fatty acid
那這個是一個脂肪酸
So it must be very Lumpol
所以它一定是非常Lumpol
There should be no water in this place
這個地方應該沒有水
it has a way to survive
它才有辦法去存活
Then of course the other four
那當然是另外四個呢
we think there is water
我們認為是有水
Excuse me
請問一下
How do you know if there is water or not?
你怎麼知道有水沒水
This is the question everyone is asking
這是大家在問的問題啊
OK, where is the water in Portain?
OK 在Portain裡面哪裡有水
where is there no water
哪裡沒水
one thing I didn't know
根本不曉得的一件事情
So I just do this challenge saying
所以我就做這個挑戰說
I'm going to challenge these things
我要去挑戰這些東西
how do i challenge
那我怎麼挑戰呢
let's look good
讓我們看好
We said there is no way to propane this water
我們說有沒有辦法Propane這個Water
This surrounding of water is in Trotopen
水的這個surrounding在Trotopen呢
we thought of it
我們就想到了啊
Isn't Trotopen like this?
Trotopen不是這樣子嗎
right
對不對
if i am here
如果我在這個地方
no matter where
不管哪裡
Change to x4, otherwise how to change
改x4 不然怎麼改
Is there a way this place can Sensing water
有沒有辦法這個地方可以Sensing水
If possible, its socket is almost the same as it
如果可以的話 它的socket跟它差不多
Can I use Protin's Expression
我可不可以用Protin的Expression的方式
For example, feed Ecolite as nutrients
譬如說 餵給Ecolite當養分
Can it become an Unnatural Protin after eating it?
它吃了以後 可不可以變成一個Unnatural的Protin
OK, is there a possibility? Mutant's Protin
OK 有沒有可能性呢 就Mutant的Protin
Is it possible? I'll fix this first.
有沒有可能呢 我就先解決這件事情
is there anything
有沒有東西可以
That’s why I didn’t talk about it just now, just pull the electrons here, right?
那剛剛不講嗎 這邊拉電子就可以 不是嗎
Just pull the electrons here.
就這拉電子就可以啊
Sorry, it's on the mountain
抱歉 就在山的位置
It just happened that your Amino-S needs to be synthesized in this place
剛好砍到你的Amino-S要合成在這個地方
so no way no way
所以不行 走不通
then you can make it through
那你才可以走得通
We want the good, halloween says, from the bad, where to add acid
我們想好 萬聖說 從壞的地方 哪裡可以增加酸性
Yes, change Time to N here
有啊 在這邊把Time變成N
Yes, if you change Time to N
對 如果把Time變成N
this place must be sour
這個地方一定是很酸
We were the first to think it must be sour
我們第一個認為它一定很酸
so is it possible to come from here to this place
所以有沒有可能從這裡到這個地方來
Sorry, this was two and a half years ago
抱歉 這是兩年半前的時候
Just tell Vice President Wang
講給王副院長就講
I will talk to Chen Ping or the concept
我就跟陳平講說 或者概念
Chen Ping said you Kiss this can't be synthesized
陳平說 你Kiss一下 這個沒辦法合成
acid
酸
I rushed in and said that there is no way to combine them, and I will show you.
我就衝了進去說沒辦法合成 我合給你看
basically
基本上來講
So the answer is that I organize a team
所以答案就是我組織一個team
just start looking
就開始去找找找
According to two or three months later, it is possible
根據兩三個月以後 有可能
so we just let it go
所以我們就放手去做
You see we still made it
你看我們還是做出來了
Let me make one, two, three, four, and five
一部兩部三部四部五部還是給我做出來
basically i'm peak camp
基本上 我是peak camp的
So this is related to organic physicochemical analysis
所以這跟有機物化分析
What volume has what peak relationship
什麼物積有什麼有什麼peak關係
Just do it, basically
就做就對了啦 基本上來講
So the answer can be made
所以答案就可以做出來
And we can also make is only l seam
而且我們還可以做出是只有l 縫
no problem at all
這一點問題都沒有
basically speaking
基本上來講的話
so made it
所以 做出來了
The answer is can it?
那答案是可不可以呢
The answer is that it is really possible after it is illuminated
答案是它照光以後真的是可以
Does water have a wave circle or something?
水 還有有波動圈什麼嗎
The answer is that one thing is really done for me.
答案一件事情是還真的給我做出來了
Basically, you can see that the spectrum we made looks like this
基本上 你看我們做出來的光譜是這樣子
I'll tell you, it's very simple
我就跟你講說 很簡單就是
The result we made is
我們做出來的結果是
n1 has the possibility of H n2 has the possibility of H
n1有可能H n2有可能H
It doesn't matter, this protein 98
沒有關係 這蛋白質98
This protein 2 will turn green after G8
這蛋白質2 因為G8以後就變成綠了
there are these two these two are this
有這兩個 這兩個就是這個
This is my non-protein transfer
跟這個就是我的一個 non-protein transfer
Shine with protein transfer
跟protein transfer放光
this is n2
這個是n2的
so all three have
所以三個都有
Then you say teacher, how do you know which one?
那你說老師你怎麼知道哪一個
We will synthesize n7A3 in 2
我們就合成有 n7A3在2的
n7A3 in 1's
n7A3在1的
We can then compare the spectra
我們就可以去比對光譜
the answer is right
答案都是對的
so we know that
所以我們知道說
it can really be water
它真的可以是用水
That is, you can go to probe water
就是可以去probe水
right in the water
就在水裡面
in the water
在水裡面
So it's really possible to probe
所以它真的是可以probe
Then of course we will take this
那當然我們就把這個
就wake it equalize
就wake it equalize
OK of course it is
OK 那當然就是
The answer to one thing is
那答案一件事情是
Because we are using expression
因為我們是用expression的方式
Do this and you will know
這個做 這個就知道
So we have five words
所以我們有五個的話
terribly sorry
很抱歉
if we are single
如果我們單一一個
what about the other four
其他四個呢
we because we don't
我們因為我們不用
know from making protein
做protein的而知道
We're not doing that Peter Schuess way
我們並不是用那個Peter Schuess的方式
But we're doing Peter Schuess now
可是我們現在是用Peter Schuess的方式
we use that called
我們用那個叫做
that that that that that
那個那個那個那個
The way of that amber coden
那個那個amber coden的方式
OK we used to be the easiest
OK 我們以前就是最簡單
If there is only one to become a trip
如果說只有一個要變成trip
For the other four, change it to
另外四個的話就把它變
So the double ball will change a bit, but the activity will not change much
所以雙球會改變一點,但是activity是不太變的
So we do it this way, you see we just replace every
所以我們用這種方式呢,你看我們就把每一個都取代
replace each one, crystal energy thing happened
把每一個都取代,晶能的事情發生了
When we replaced him, we found out that you see this in the water
當我們把他取代以後,發現說你看這在水裡面是這樣
Three, but in Porting there are two
三根,可是在Porting裡面就是兩個
N2 is missing, why? Because the water inside is not Bock water
N2不見了,為什麼?因為裡面的水不是Bock水
So this N2 is gone, that is, Equilibrium is gone
所以這N2就不見,就是Equilibrium就不見了
If you don't see it, there are two. It doesn't matter if there are two, there must be water.
那不見就是兩個,兩個沒關係,就有一定有水
There must be water, this catalysis, but the place of W65
這一定有水,這催化,可是W65的地方
If W65 is replaced by ours, no, 0
W65地方換成我們的話,沒有,0
just no water, really no water
就是沒有水,真的是沒有水
So using this place, I can probe and say, oh! This porting is in this part of W65
所以用這個地方我就可以probe說,喔!這個Porting裡面在W65的這個
This Si'an acid has no water, and the others have water, OK
這個四安酸是沒有水的,其他都有水,OK
I won’t tell you about other things, other places have water, OK
其他我就不跟你看,其他這個地方都有水,OK
Then you say, hey! Then how accurate is this? It’s very simple, you see! After I put Dinatio
那你說,欸!那這個到底怎麼準,很簡單,你看喔!我把Dinatio以後
After taking this SomboxinDinatio, it's back to three roots
把這個SomboxinDinatio以後,又回到三根了
Dinatio catches all the water, he's coming back
Dinatio全部都接住水,他要回來
So of course it's incredible
所以當然就是不可思議
Which means I can really go pub water with this
就是說我真的可以用這個去pub水
So I throw this out
所以這篇就我丟出去
Actually sorry we lost it to Nature
其實抱歉我們是丟到Nature
Nature saved eight months
Nature省了八個月
tell us you want
跟我們講說你要
At least three or four examples
起碼三四個example
For each example, we have to do it for at least half a year to a year
每個example要做我們起碼半年到一年
Three or four need to be done for two years
三四個都要做兩年
no time to wait
沒有時間等了
basically
基本上來講
we say we don't have time to wait
我們說我們沒有時間等
he said no time to wait
他說沒有時間等
We will recommend you to Nature Communication
我們就把你recommend到Nature Communication
So publish Nature Communication
所以發表Nature Communication
Basically they are very
基本上他們就非常的
very surprise
非常的surprise
Say oh, you can pub
說喔 竟然可以pub
water in pub protein
pub protein裡面的水
Let's continue to look down
我們繼續看下來
So the catastrophe temperature is in this place
所以大災溫在這個地方
1. Where does protein water exist?
一 蛋白質水存在哪些區域
What is its structure near the active site
他在活性部位的附近的結構是怎麼樣
It's interesting
這很有趣
Whether these water molecules form a clear mass
是否這些水分子形成清見團處期
The specificity of the structure and the resulting dynamics
結構的特殊性及所衍生的動態
Are structural changes related to protein activity?
結構變化和蛋白質活性有關呢
How to perform hydration reaction during protein finishing?
蛋白質整理時是如果進行水合反應呢
This is one of the things we are most interested in
這是我們最有興趣的一件事情
Basically written in both Chinese and English
基本上其實白中英文寫
Change it to Chinese this morning
今天早上把它改成中文
Tired OK let's see
很累 OK 我們看
So in biochemical reproduction
所以在生化生育中
So basically this is why everyone can't figure it out
所以基本上這是大家不能解出的原因
The reason is that so far
原因是目前為止
no direct
沒有可以直接
carbon increase in biochemical moisture content
碳就生化水分質的碳增
Analysis of protein water by X-ray is static
X-ray對蛋白質的水的解析是靜態的
OK water quality position is the result of optimization
OK 水分質位置是最佳化的結果
everybody knows
大家都知道
basically impossible
基本上是不可能的
but we can really go
可是我們就真的可以去
Well this year and a half
好 這一年半
One and a half years since publication
從發表以後這一年半
We've actually found two examples
我們其實已經找到兩個例子
OK let's give an example
OK 我們舉一個例子
This is a very simple
這個就是一個很簡單
just one
就是一個
this
這個
Rhypo Nucrease
Rhypo Nucrease
OK cuts the RNA
OK 就切斷RNA的
It only has a Triple Fent
它只有一個Triple Fent
As far as the location of W59
就W59的位置
OK, what about this one?
OK 那這個呢
when we go to prop it
當我們去Prop它
We also use Protin's Expression
我們一樣用Protin的Expression
It's better to change one
一個最好換嘛
One I don't do anything OK
一個我不要做任何動作 OK
you know we won't talk
你就知道我們就不講
tell you the result
跟你講結果
I'll tell you the result
結果就跟你講說
We really prop it dynamic
我們真的Prop它動態
when it does have water
它確實是有水的時候
Do Equilibrium when there is no water
還有沒水的時候做Equilibrium
This is something no one has ever seen
這個是從來沒有人看過
OK we see it Equilibrium
OK 我們看到它Equilibrium
What do you say
那你說
You said that your spectral solution looks like this
你說你光譜解數出來是這樣子
Excuse me, do you really have
請問一下你真的是有
have
有
According to us, teacher Yang Xiaoqing from the Fuda University
根據我們就那個輔大那個楊曉清老師
he does a test
他就做一個測試
OK let's see this is his Wipe of Neucrase
OK 我們看這個是他的Wipe of Neucrase
I'm looking at these two loops
我這邊看這兩個loop
In fact it is very loose
事實上是很loose
You see every time he is doing evolution
你看他每次在做evolution的時候
every time doing this
每次在做這個
he is very loose
他是非常loose
So of course water can run in like this all the time
所以當然是水就一直這樣可以跑進來
After running in, basically talk
那跑進來以後基本上來講話
In fact we are prop in this place
事實上我們是prop在這個地方
OK so you can tell one thing is
OK 所以你可以看出來一件事情是
basically talk
基本上來講話
it slowly water will come out
它慢慢慢慢水就會出來
OK so it will come out
OK 所以就會出來
so maybe one thing
所以大概一件事情
it does have an in and an out
它確實是有一個in 一個out
in one out one out
in 一個out 一個out
action that has been doing
一直在做的動作
OK basically
OK 基本上
This is an interesting example
這是很有趣的一個例子
just tell everyone
就跟各位講
What about the second example?
那第二個例子呢
We've been doing something more interesting recently
我們最近在做一個更有趣的事情
is doing this Aspirogenase
就是在做這個Aspirogenase
So why is Aspirogenase so important
那為什麼Aspirogenase這麼重要
Everyone knows one thing is
大家都知道一件事情是
This is treating it as medicine
這個是把它當作藥
OK it can cure cancer
OK 它可以治療cancer
then why
那為什麼呢
Because tumor cells
因為tumor cell
basically talk
基本上來講話
It is sensitization without Aspirogenase
它是沒有Aspirogenase的sensitization
OK so that means
OK 所以意思就是說
If you wear Aspirogenase outside
如果你穿外面的Aspirogenase
If you change aspargion into aspargionase
把aspargion變成aspargionase的話
you eat it and it's over
你拿吃下去它就完了
Why? Because it doesn't turn it into
為什麼?因為它不會把它變成
so it dies
所以它就死掉
If you just feed it aspargion it will live
如果你直接給它吃aspargion它就活了
OK, so if you use aspargionase
OK,所以你用aspargionase的話
After cutting this off, it's basically OK
把這砍掉以後基本上就OK
Then this aspargionase has two states
那這個aspargionase有兩種態
One is called ANSAA type
一種叫ANSAA type
One B is Type 1, Type 2
一種B就 Type 1, Type 2
The activity of Type 2 is Type 1
那Type 2的這個activity是Type 1的
About 100 times more active
大概是100倍的活性
Let's talk about why we don't understand
我們講說為什麼我們不懂
only one
只有一個
it only has one
它總共只有一個
This chiptopin 68 and chiptopin 66 are in this place
這個chiptopin 68跟chiptopin 66在這個地方
So we said can we pop it?
所以我們說我們可以pop它嗎?
OK, let's replace it as well
OK,我們一樣把它置換掉
OK, after doing mutation
OK,做mutation以後
We found an incredible thing
我們發現一個不可思議的事情
Look, the first red line
看,第一條紅線
The red line is soboxen
紅線是soboxen
When there was water in that soboxen just now
剛剛那個soboxen就有水的時候
Then come on
然後呢,來線
no water, this place is waterless
沒有水,這個地方是沒有水的
B type is without water
B type是沒有水
So 100 times more active is without water
所以100倍活性更強的就是沒有水
What's more, this one has water
那另外呢,這個是有水的
But what is it where there is water?
可是它有水的地方是它的什麼
Only 1¾
才1¾
So we know this place has water or no water
所以我們知道這個地方有水沒水
You do the equilibrium first
你先做equilibrium
I won't talk much
我就不多講
All I can say is why this place
只可以講說為什麼這個地方
why is this place ok
為什麼這個地方OK
its activity is so high
它的活性是這麼高
because it has no water
因為它沒有水
no water and no
沒有水又沒有
All water relay system words
所有的water relay system的話
it makes this place adjustable
它讓它這個地方可以調整
It is very flexible
就是可以很flexible
So this place is very active
所以這個地方它的活性很強
For now, we interpret it like this
我們現在暫時是這樣解釋
we just finished this one
我們這個剛把它弄完
so everyone one thing
所以大家一件事情
We think one thing is to say
我們認為一件事情就是說
the water is half active in this place
水在這個地方半著活性的
very very important role
非常非常重要的角色
There is no water in this place
這個地方是沒有水的
Then let's go to x-ray
那我們再去看x-ray
Because both of these have x-ray
因為這兩個都有x-ray
unbelievable
不可思議
but i don't believe in x-ray
但我不相信x-ray
But there is no water in x-ray
可是x-ray這個地方沒有水
this place has water
這個地方是有水的
ok
ok
How accurate is the x-ray
那x-ray多準
i don't know
我不曉得
can only talk
只可以講說
the result we made
我們做出來的結果
we go to x-ray
我們去對x-ray
really like this
真的是這樣子
This place really has no water
這個地方確實是沒水
there is water in this area
這方面是有水
ok basically
ok 基本上來講
So we know one thing is
所以我們知道一件事情是
where it differs is
它不一樣的地方是
there is really no water
真的是有水沒水
Make another equilibrium
再做一個equilibrium
ok basically
ok 基本上
then we have sent this to pns
那這我們已經送到pns
At least it's starting to save
起碼它開始省了
ok basically
ok 基本上來講
just tell you
就跟你講說
water in this place
水在這個地方
play a very, very important role
搬演一個非常非常重要的角色
ok
ok
Then you say in this place
那你說在這個地方
what else can we do
我們還可以做什麼呢
Let me give you the simplest example, okay?
我舉個最簡單的例子好不好
let's watch this
我們看這個
this so-called
這個所謂的
In time microbial
In time microbial
Peptide
Peptide
One is melittin
一個就是蜂毒素
Shaking
Milatine
There is only one Tripdopene in Milatine
Milatine裡面只有一個Tripdopene
at this place
在這個地方
should be all
應該這是所有的
The 26 Amino Acid
這個26個Amino Acid
There is a Tripdopene in the middle
中間有一個是Tripdopene
OK
OK
i can replace it
我可以把它換掉
why change
為什麼換掉
because it is a thorn
因為它是刺
it destroys the cell membrane
它是破壞細胞膜
But it cuts on the cell membrane
可是它是砍在細胞膜上面
it cuts on the cell membrane
它砍在細胞膜上面
then it breaks a hole
然後它破個洞
It dies after a hole is made
破個洞以後它就死掉
OK, this shot kills basically
OK 這射就死掉基本上來講
If it is Indolissidine
那如果是Indolissidine
this is melittin
這是蜂毒素
This is Indolissidine
這個是Indolissidine
Indolissidine was two years ago
Indolissidine是兩年前
just what
剛剛什麼
Just unblocked
剛剛解禁出來了
It is the most useful treatment for Hong Kong feet
就是治療香港腳最有用
You see, Hong Kong foot was very difficult to treat before, right?
你看那香港腳以前就很難治對不對
Now just put it on Indolissidine
現在只要把它在Indolissidine的話
Just paint it on and it'll be fine
塗一塗馬上就好
If you are unlucky, you can try
不幸的話你們可以試試看
And those feet and gray paper
還有那個什麼腳什麼灰白紙
What are you doing?
加幹嘛幹嘛
fuck you know so touch
搞你知道這麼摸一摸
or good luck
或者有口福的
promise to be fine soon
保證馬上好
In the past, it was impossible for any page to be good this year.
以前是根本今年哪一頁都不能好了
why don't you go back and try
不如你回去試試看
I promise you this thing is OK
我給你保證這件事情OK
So when a thing is
所以當一件事情是
It destroys the entire cell membrane
它是把整個細胞膜破壞掉
Then the microbial dies
然後這個microbial就死掉
basically in this way
基本上是用這種方式
then this is better
那這個比較好
there is only one
這只有一個
So we're going to nuke here
所以我們就核子這裡
look we look at this thing
你看我們來看這件事情
look at this place
你看這個地方
we are simple
我們就很簡單
Because as long as we cut to this place
因為我們只要是砍到這個地方
This is Haizuo phobic
這是海左phobic
no water
沒有水
Look when there is no water
沒有水以後你看
our place
我們這個地方
Change it to our tritophan
改成我們的這個tritophan的話
Changed to the words of tritophan, the suppression claw of our second district
改成我們二區打壓爪tritophan的話
Seven seconds after you look in
你看一進去以後七秒鐘
this place was supposed to be like this
這個地方本來是這樣子
grow up like this
馬上變成這樣長大
Why?
為什麼?
because there is no water
因為已經無水了
This is with water and this is without water
這是有水這是無水
i can grow up now
我可以馬上長大
OK
OK
so in seven seconds it goes in
所以七秒鐘它就進去
Then we use a so-called
那我們用一個所謂的叫做
cover yellow green tree
蓋黃綠樹
just a guts
就是一個膽料
Guts are when the outside meets the inside
膽料就是在外面跟裡面的時候
it is different emission
它是不一樣的emission
OK
OK
So one thing to be
所以待一件事情是
This seven seconds it cut up
這個七秒鐘它就砍上去了
But it takes 45 seconds
可是要45秒
this will break
這個才會破掉
Come in after breaking
破掉以後就進來
So it is also a beautiful starly
所以也是滿漂亮的一個starly
just tell you
就跟你講說
Its application is Eyeless Buddha Realm
它的應用就是無眼佛界
OK
OK
This is just one of the examples
這只是one of the examples
just tell you one thing
就跟各位講一件事情
Then we will challenge
那我們將來挑戰
What is your challenge?
你挑戰什麼呢?
i want to challenge this
我要挑戰這個
OK
OK
but i talk about this stuff
但我講這個東西
Everyone eats this bottle
每個都吃這一瓶
Like how is it possible
比如說怎麼可能性
I want to challenge the protein channel is
我要挑戰蛋白質通道就是
acroprin
acroprin
ok acroprin recently in Science Nature
ok acroprin最近在Science Nature
Two days in a row
連發兩天
ok, let me tell you that he released the X-ray
ok就跟你講他解除X-ray出來
That's seven water
就這個有七個水
Big Dipper Water
北斗七星水
Let's talk here
這邊再說
we see it this way
我們這樣看說
After entering, the water
進去以後到底這個水
ok if we change it to a
ok如果我們這邊改成一個
trip top
trip top
Our artificial trip top
我們的那個 artificial trip top
how about
請問一下怎麼樣
but everyone eats themselves
但是每個人都吃自己
For example, please, this is membrane protein
比如說拜託啦這是 membrane protein
How could you come out of Isox-ray
你怎麼可能Isox-ray出來
I thought
我本來以為說
I was scolded as a bloody sprinkler, right?
我被罵了狗血噴頭對不對
The result was scolded
結果被罵了
in another month
再過一個月以後
People really released his Isox-ray
人家真的把他Isox-ray出來了
ok so now he can put
ok所以現在他可以把
trunk
tronket
ok put him out of isox-ray
ok把他Isox-ray出來
So we've got this now
所以我們現在已經拿到這個
this protocol
這個 protocol
ok we are doing it now
ok我們現在正在做
But it's a super challenge
不過這是一個超級挑戰
because acroprin is too big
因為 acroprin太大了
ok basically speaking
ok基本上來講的話
OK, what about synthesis?
好那在合成方面呢
We've been working on this
我們一直在進行這方面的
ok all this
ok所有這方面的
Synthesis of ok
的合成 ok
why
為什麼呢
Because we want to synthesize this
因為我們要想合成這個
brighter
放光更強的
ok more sensitive
ok更sensitive
what
幹嘛
So we're developing this thing right now
所以我們現在在發展這個東西
ok i'm here
好我在這邊
let you breathe
讓你們呼吸一下
ok stop
ok stop
this change the gear
這個change the gear
what about ok gear
ok gear呢
The above is more fun. Let me talk about the nano-resistant materials of these semiconductors.
上面更好玩 我來講一下這些半導體的耐米機材
it's a lot of fun
這是一個很好玩的事
so i'm talking about this place now
所以我現在在講這個地方
This place is about me from 2002 to 2009
這個地方大概就是我2002年到2009年
OK self-discipline is developing
OK 蠻自律在發展的
After 2009 I think
那2009年以後我認為
In fact, my eyesight is enough
其實我的眼光還是夠的
I think this should have been commercialized
我認為這本來就應該商業化了
OK, so after 2010, I actually didn’t publish much
OK 所以2010年以後其實我就不太發表
what have you been doing
一直在做什麼
Do some kind of mass production or something
做某種量產或幹嘛的動作
because I think it's supposed to be
因為我覺得這本來就應該是
It's time to start applying
開始要去做應用的時間了
Let's see what's interesting about this place
我們來看看這個地方有什麼有趣的事情
The first one, of course, is quantum dots.
第一個當然講的就是量子點
on the mine road
就礦登道
That mine is basically talking
那礦登道基本上還講話
When it comes to mining roads, it's actually very simple.
那講到礦登道其實很簡單
I'll just give you an example
我隨便舉個例子好了
We say vulcanized
我們說硫化隔
or petrified
或者是石化隔
or shaved septum
或者剃化隔
OK these things please
OK 這些東西拜託啊
This NASA has been using since 50 years ago
這個NASA從50年前就開始用
What's so strange, it's made of solar panels or something
什麼稀奇 它做太陽能板什麼東西
It's something everyone knows, right?
大家都知道的一個事情啊 對不對
But have you ever seen these things glow?
可是你有看過這些東西發光
Did you light it? Impossible
你照光的嗎?不可能嘛
isn't it? does it shine when you shine it? it's metallic
對不對?你照光它會發光嗎?它就是金屬光澤
Just like the semi-conductive metal that Dürr's luster
就半導體金屬那個杜爾的光澤
If you shine more light on it, it will become hotter
你照光它更不放光,它就變熱
So why is it like this? Why isn't it glowing?
那為什麼會這樣子?它為什麼不發光?
A very simple thing, let me give you an example, which involves
很簡單的一件事情,我舉個例子,這就是涉及到
The so-called machine problem is called excitement
所謂的機子的問題,叫excitement
As far as the machine is concerned, let me give you the simplest example
就機子的問題,我舉個最簡單的例子
For example, optimistic, red and white as CDSE or CDS
譬如說看好,紅白當作CDSE或CDS
It doesn't matter, that is, it has formed a CDSE
都沒有關係,就是它已經形成一個CDSE的
The fast material of semiconductor is good
半導體的這個快材好了
As for the fast material, if I arouse
這快材呢,假設我一激發
Once excited, an electron
一激發以後呢,就是把一個電子
Kick from this ground state to the kickstand
從這個ground state去踢到激發台
There is a game in semiconductors, kick to the excitation stage
半導體就有一個game,踢到激發台
As soon as you kick to the trigger table, here is the fast material
你一踢到激發台以後,這下面是快材
So after an electron from below kicks up, it stays in a hole
所以下面的一個電子踢上去以後,就留在一個洞
As for this hole, the electrons next to it will always go back... keep filling it.
這個洞呢,馬上旁邊的電子就一直回...一直填嘛
So when the electrons are filling, it seems that the hole is moving
所以電子在填的時候,好像洞在走
Electronics are filling in, you can see that we are playing that crossball
電子在填,你看我們在玩那個crossball就知道
There's a hole here, you fill it in
這個有個洞,你一填
It's not that you can't move
這不是就不能動
move
動動動
so it seems
所以好像是
In fact, the electron is going
其實電子在走了
But the reflection seems to be moving electric
可是反光好像電動在走
As far as the defender's electric is going
就國防士的電動在走
there is a movement
就有個動在走
You are basically empty above
你基本上其實上面是空的
So this electron is free to move
所以這個電子可以自由移動
Right, so the electrons are also going
對不對 所以電子也在走
So this electron is also going
所以這個電子也在走
Electric is also running here
這邊電動也在走
OK when will it shine
OK 什麼時候它會放光
it's easy
很簡單啦
this is the electron
就是這個電子
OK Liang Sanbo also pay attention
OK 梁三伯也注意
It is this electron that touches this electric
就是這個電子碰到這個電動
For position
對位置的
down it shines
下來它就放光
can i ask one thing
可不可以請問一件事情
When an electron and an electric
當一個電子跟電動
if you think of it as a boat
你把它當作是一條小船的話
OK think of this place as the Pacific Ocean
OK 把這個地方當作太平洋
There is a boat in the Pacific
太平洋有一條小船
sudden lightning strike
突然閃電一擊
just after the light
就照光以後
lightning strike in half
閃電一擊變兩半
OK, what about the two halves?
OK 請問這兩半
words wandering in the pacific
在太平洋中亂走的話
what is the chance of it overlapping
它重合機率多大
0 impossible things
0 不可能的事情
But if you take this Pacific Ocean
可是如果你把這個太平洋
Keep chopping and chopping into seven Lianpeng
一直砍砍砍成七連鵬
even cut into smaller smaller smaller
甚至砍成更小更小更小
If you cut it down to such a small area
砍到一個這麼小的範圍的話
Will this be a reunion?
這樣會不會重合會啊
yes so it's that simple
對 所以就這麼簡單
So we cut this block all the way
所以我們就把這個塊材一直砍
If the way of top down
如果說top down的方式
What will I do with the e-bin?
用e-bin的話會幹嘛
just keep hacking
就一直砍砍砍
cut to small
砍到小到
as small as the two of them
小到他們兩個
also have mutual attraction
還互相有attraction
mutual attraction
互相有attraction
This is the so-called wave radius
這個就是所謂的波radius
We call it the Bohr radius
我們叫波耳半徑
just write the hydrogen atom
就寫那個hydrogen atom
In terms of Bohr radius
就波耳半徑
just below this radius
就在這個半徑之下
it also mutual
它還互相
if you feel each other
有感覺到互相的話
it can overlap
它就可以重合
right
對不對
Then this varies with your material
那這個隨著你的材質不同而不同
I feel like something is in a long place
我覺得什麼東西在很長的地方
You can also learn from each other
還可以互相類來一招
There is PBS
有PBS
flow chemical fiber
就流化纖
that is very long
那個很長
it can still know
它都還可以知道
basically
基本上
like CWG is ok
像CWG還可以
Probably about 15 or 20 nm
大概是差不多15、20個nm
it also knows
它還知道
so we chop it chop chop chop
所以我們把它砍砍砍砍
Cut to 15 nm
砍到15個nm
or around 10 nm
或10個nm左右的話
It has the opportunity to overlap the electron and the electric
它就有機會電子跟電動就可以重合
If it does not coincide with the previous
那如果不重合以前
promising
看好
Suppose there is an electric
假如說這邊有個電動
electronic
電子
Electrons go around like this
電子這樣繞著走
that's not like anything
那不是很像什麼
very much like
很像
Aten isn't it? Electrons go around electrics
Aten不是嗎?電子繞著電動在走
Isn't it? OK
不是嗎?OK
So all the formulas are the same
所以所有的公式都是一樣的
That is, when the Size is larger
就是Size越大的時候
Its Gap is smaller
它的Gap就越小
The smaller the Size, the larger the Gap
Size越小的時候Gap就越大
why? because it's the same
為什麼?因為它是跟這個一樣
Have you ever learned Particle in a box
你有沒有學過Particle in a box
Just tell you about Particle in a box
就跟你講說Particle in a box
When we leave the table now
我們檯面現在走的時候
The longer the distance, the smaller the Energy gap
距離越長的時候它的Energy gap就越小
Is this the same?
這一樣嘛
When you cut bigger, its Energy gap gets smaller
當你越砍得越大一點它的Energy gap越小
Therefore, the long wavelength and short wavelength of its light are related to its
所以說它的放光的長波長短波長是跟它的
What about it? It has something to do with its radius
跟它的什麼?跟它的半徑是有關係的
OK like this
OK這樣子
Then why does it shine?
那為什麼它可以放光?
The reason is that we cut it to
原因就是我們把它砍到
It also knows that it can find itself
它互相還知道可以找得到自己
OK it will shine
OK它就會放光
I use this simplest explanation
我用這種最簡單的解釋
if you want to explain the words in your eyes
如果你要解釋眼裡的話
It's okay if it takes two hours, everyone.
大家要兩小時算了不用OK
just in this way you know what to say
就用這種方式你就知道說
It shines because you cut it down to the Bohr radius
它會放光原因就是你把它砍到波耳半徑
OK, the Boer radius varies with the material
OK這波耳半徑之下隨著材質不同
it just shines
它就這個就會放光
The size of the emitted light wavelength
放光的波長的大小
OK the wavelength is shorter when you're younger
OK當你越小的時候波長越短
The larger the OK, the longer the wavelength
OK 越大的時候波長就越長
with this method
用這種方式
According to this you know one thing is
根據這樣你就知道一件事情是
how do you synthesize it
那你怎麼合成呢
OK
OK
I just cut it, right?
我剛剛是用砍的對不對
You can also use this method called top down
你也可以用這個叫top down的方式
you can use button up
你可以用button up
chemical synthesis
就用化學的合成
It's very simple to let each atom like this
很簡單就讓一個一個atom這樣
keep accumulating, accumulating, accumulating somewhere
一直累積累積累積到某個地方
stop
停下來
how to stop
怎麼停
How do you know its size?
你怎麼知道它Size多大呢
We all use wavelengths of light
我們都用放光的波長
shine down
放光下來
stop it stop it
停就把它停下來
OK this way
OK 用這種方式
If you want to stop before, you will soon
以前要停的話就要很快
stop in seconds
幾秒鐘就要停
not now
現在不用
wait till i get on with it
等一下我講下去就知道
minutes now
現在幾分鐘都可以
used to be like this
以前都這樣
So of course ours is easy
所以當然我們這種很簡單嘛
For example, if you want a CD
譬如說你要CD
I want to do CDSE
我要做CDSE
Whole body of your CD
你的CD的那個全體物
Just use a complex
就是用一個complex
Let's call this Oligosacid oleic acid
我們就把這個Oligosacid油酸
Just cut it into a complex like this
就這樣把它砍成一個complex
Then, the abbreviation is to use a high temperature
然後呢 縮本就是用一個高溫的
because we are in high temperature
因為我們在高溫
we want high temperature synthesis
我們要高溫成合
So use this Oxothexate at high temperature
所以用高溫的這個Oxothexate
you are ok
你可以OK
Then SE
然後SE
OK we also want to use complex
OK 我們也是要用complex
OK use this complex
OK 用這種complex
I often talk about TOP, TW is this thing
常常講TOP,TW就是這個東西
is forcefing
就是forcefing
with this method
用這種方式
so in this way
所以用這種方式呢
this is picasso, this is picasso two
這個是picasso,這是picasso兩個
That is, the whole district is organized in this sauver
就是全區在這個sauver裡面去組
Then what are these picasso these
然後這些picasso這些又當作什麼
as its surfactant
當作它的介面活性劑
Why surfactant? It's simple
為什麼介面活性劑?很簡單嘛
Do you want to use chemistry to grow
你是要用化學去長
What is the most stable?
最穩定是什麼?
fast material
快材
If you don't restrict it, it will definitely become fast material
你如果不把它限制住,它一定會變快材
How do you limit it? It's simple
你怎麼把它限制住?很簡單
in a template
在個模板裡面展
What is this template?
這個模板是什麼東西?
Yes, surfactants can form enveloping
有啊,介面活性劑可以形成圍包嘛
Use the bag as a template
就圍包當作一個模板
Let it grow this thing, it's that simple
讓它去長這個東西,就這麼簡單
You can go to probi for the bag
那圍包你可以去probi
like a long bag or a
像長的圍包或者是
Generally, except that there are more bags
一般都是除了圍包比較多
What does a long bag grow into?
長的圍包就長成什麼?
grow into a wild or rod
長成wild或rod
so you grow into a quantum dot
這樣你就長成一個量子點
let's take a look
我們來看下來
So in this way you know
所以用這種方式你就知道
I'm trying to tell you this
我這個是試意圖就跟你講
Then we probably use it like this for a long time
那我們長的話大概就用這樣子
put this with this
就把這個跟這個
Cut the two together and add to 300 degrees
兩個砍在一起 加到300度
up to 300 degrees and basically
加到300度 然後基本上
Of course, this is actually cooking to 300 degrees first
當然說其實是這個先 cooking到300度
cast this in
把這個鑄進去了
cast in and what you get
鑄進去你就得到什麼
get this next to
得到這個旁邊
These are all interfacial agents that can be used as it
這些都是可以當作它的介面活進劑
cut it down
把它砍住
make it only spawn in a sphere or something
讓它只產生在一個球狀或幹嘛
Then stop where you see the light
那你看到放光在哪裡就停下來
It only knows about the size
它就 size 大概多大就知道
For example, 5 nil only ones are about to shine
比如說5個nil only的大概放光
all in yellow
都在黃色的地方
Wait a minute and I'll show you
等一下我給你看就知道
so you know what to say
所以你就知道說這些
In fact, they are all grown in this way.
其實都是用這種方式來長的
This is the easiest way ok
這最簡單的一種方式ok
It's a pity that the light emitted by such growth is very weak
可惜這樣長出來的放光都很弱
what is the reason
原因是什麼
because you also know one thing
因為你也知道一件
when you get smaller and smaller
當你越小越小越小的時候
How about it
怎麼樣
We call service to volume and it gets bigger and bigger
我們叫service to volume就越來越大
What is service to volume
什麼叫service to volume
This is the interface
就是這個介面
to process to volume
去處理到 volume
In fact, the interface is more and more
其實介面是越來越多了
You also know how to learn this
你也知道學這個
Learn without ability
學無機能就知道
what is the interface
介面都是什麼
are all flaws
都是缺陷
interface stuff
介面的東西
All interfaces are dangling bombs
所有的介面都是dangling bomb
Why
為什麼
because everything else is fine
因為其他都是接好的
Did you face the air?
你面對空氣是沒有接
Or face liquid is not connected
或面對液體是沒有接的
So this place is full of flaws
所以這個地方全部都是缺陷
If the electron hits up or electric it
如果電子一打上去或電動它
it will be trap
它就會被trap
will be there now
就會被現在那裡面
It doesn't shine, just change to this
它就不放光了 就變這個
So it doesn't work that way.
所以這樣做出來其實都不行
If that doesn't work, what should I do?
那不行怎麼辦呢
Of course, many people do just use
當然有很多人做就是用
The so-called call share method
所謂call share的方式
It's next to it. When it grows to this place, take it out.
就旁邊呢 長到這個地方拿出來以後
Then go in and grow another layer of ZNS
再進去再去長一層ZNS
The total ZN's precursor and s's precursor are one layer longer
總ZN的precursor跟s的precursor再長一層
ok then like this
ok 那這樣子的話
If the side is more enclosed
旁邊就比較包住的話
There's no flaws in this place, shine
這個地方就沒有缺陷 放光
why doesn't it come here from the electron
為什麼它不會從電子從頭跑到這邊來
because of what in this place
因為這個地方的什麼
The so-called varensband of this place
這個地方的所謂的varensband
跟conduction band
跟conduction band
Just how to translate varensband
就是varensband怎麼翻
Electrical strap and conductive strap
架電帶跟導電帶
ok, this one is higher than it
ok 都是這個比它高的比較高
So electrons won't go out Electric won't go out
所以電子不會出去 電動不會出去
So it is now here
所以它就被現在這裡面
it shines in this place
它就放光放在這個地方
At this time, the light is very strong
這個時候放光就很強
ok so use this way
ok 所以用這種方式
what will you get
你就會得到什麼呢
different size you see
不同的size 你看
This is
這是
Its radius is 1.7nm 1.9 2.2 2.6 3.0
它的半徑是1.7nm 1.9 2.2 2.6 3.0
Just 30 N Shuang
就30個N爽
Let’s see who it is, the wavelength of its light is getting longer and longer
上一上看 誰就這樣它的放光就越來越長波長
From more than 400 to more than 600
從400多到600多
It is possible to get the Hongchen Huangli combustion battery
都可能就得到紅塵黃麗燃電池
In total this is done in seconds
這個總共這樣做是在幾秒鐘完成
This can be done in about two or three minutes
這個大概在兩三分鐘內就可以完成
Organic health
有機的康胖
If you want to make red dust Huang Li combustion battery
如果你要做成紅塵黃麗燃電池
you wait slowly
你慢慢等吧
You have to do different things, the light is so strong
你要做不同東西 放光都這麼強
probably several years
大概要好幾年
But it does it for you in three minutes
可是它在三分鐘之內就給你完成
so you get what you want
所以你要得到什麼就得到什麼東西
What's more, it's not over yet
更何況還沒有講完
because it is a version without these molecules
因為它是沒有這些分子的版本
Only FORNONG Only the vibration of biomass
只有FORNONG 只有生質的振動
So its full width at half maximum when it is shining is very narrow.
所以它的放光的時候的半高寬是很窄的
so narrow
就這麼窄
ok let's see
好 我們看看
Of course I'll show you the sex first
當然是我先給你演見為性
So when I was coming yesterday, I asked my students to say
所以我昨天要來的時候就叫我學生說
Make a batch for me tonight
晚上給我合成一批出來
So he immediately put together a batch
所以他就馬上合成一批出
mentor this is it
導師這個就是它
OK let's see how this goes
OK 我們看這個會怎麼樣
I wrapped it in a plastic bag
我是把它包在塑膠袋裡面
Because it's pretty poisonous
因為這種還是蠻毒的
Basically I don't want to take it out
基本上我就不想把它拿出來
ok let's see
好 我們看看
I just take this light, it's beautiful
我就照這個光 很漂亮
did you see
有沒有看到
Have you seen the red dust yellow green blue tissue paper?
紅塵黃綠藍綿紙有沒有看到
OK, it's really beautiful, that's all
OK 真的很漂亮 就這樣子
The student made it for me last night
學生是昨天晚上做的給我的
look how fast you can make these things
你看看要做這些東西有多快
like this
就這樣子
OK so you see it's shining every box occipital lobe
OK 所以你看它的放光每個框枕葉
Probably above 0.7 0.6
大概都是 0.7 0.6 以上的
definitely above
絕對是以上的
OK it's that strong
OK 就這麼強
OK so of course you know one thing
OK 所以當然你就知道一件事情
even blu-ray i'm now
甚至藍光的 我現在是
I know people like Mr. Lin
我知道像譬如林老師
They just make a bunch of blue ones
他們就做一堆什麼Blue的
Molecule of what
幹嘛的分子
Look, it's Super Blue
你看這是超強Blue的
This super strong Blue's words
這超強Blue的話
Quantaneers is definitely 1
Quantaneers 絕對是1的
OK look how strong it is
OK 你看它有多強
I, you already see a little blue here
我 你在這邊就已經看到一點藍了
OK this doesn't seem to be visible
OK 這個看起來看不到
No because of course because of being blocked
不是 因為當然是因為被Block住了
This super strong blue light
這超強藍光的
this is basically
這基本上
So of course one thing is to say
所以當然一件事情就是說
you use this way you know what to say
你用這種方式你就知道說
it can definitely be done
它絕對是可以做
with this method
用這種方式
But in this way there is a
但是用這種方式有一個
There is only one shortcoming
就是目前來講只有一個缺點
you said you made this
你說你做出這樣
What are you going to develop next?
你下面要怎麼發展什麼東西呢
I think just one is very simple is to put these two
我覺得剛剛是一個很簡單是把這兩個
Cut it off and say to light it in this place
把它砍住說要放光在這個地方
Then this is called TAP1
那這個叫TAP1
You can also change the different put this electron put it
你也可以改變不同把這個電子把它
Move out, look, let me move out for you to see
動出來啊 你看我動出來給你看
you see i can also say
你看我也可以說
For a TAP2, these two are stepped
一個TAP2的就這兩個是階梯式的
stepwise you see after stimulating it
階梯式的你看 激發它以後
Electronics are here Electricity has come here
電子在這邊 電動已經跑到這邊來
OK so e electric thus in this place
OK 所以電子電動從而在這個地方
it becomes short wavelength at 900
它就變成短波長在900
900 NM
900的NM
Look, it doesn't matter how you adjust it.
你看那怎麼調都沒有關係啊
I can go all the way from here to blue
我就可以從這邊藍色一直調
It is no problem to transfer to INFARATE
調到INFARATE都沒有問題啊
OK let alone these things
OK 更何況這些東西
because it has only the motion of procreation
因為它只有生子的運動
OK so it doesn't have what we call
OK 所以它沒有我們叫做
Energy Gaprow
Energy Gaprow
OK where are you shining
OK 你在什麼地方放光
You know when it's tuned right it can shine very brightly
你知道調得好它就可以放光很強
I'll see it right away
我等一下馬上可以看
But this place still doesn't work
可是這個地方還是不行
you see it doesn't work like this why not
你看像這樣不行為什麼不行
Because the electric on this outer layer
因為這外面這層的電動
OK is still flawed on the outside
OK 在外面還是缺陷
So outside you can paint a TAP1
所以外面你可以塗一個TAP1
cut it down
把它砍住
If these two use this to cut it down, it will be very strong
這兩個用這個去把它砍住的話這就會很強
If you are unlucky, I will show you
那不幸的話我給各位看
You see, if there is only one layer of CDSE, the light shines
你看如果說只有一層CDSE的時候放光在
Li Guang is here
曆光在這裡
shine here
放光在這裡
Let the light shine here when you are on the second floor
OK 兩層的時候放光在這裡
It's already 900, but it's very weak
已經900了喔 可是很弱
I put two layers outside to patch up a layer of ZNS
我把兩層外面去補一層ZNS
After chopping it down, the light is so strong
把它砍住以後放光這麼強
This light energy has already reached almost 1 in one ear.
這光能一耳已經達到快1了
at 900
在900喔
Which one can you put in the organic health can reach 900
有機康放哪個可以到900
It's light energy, one ear and one ear, it can't be type
是光能一耳一耳 不可能是型啊
It doesn't matter if the 900 can't see it, use night vision goggles
那900看不到沒有關係 用夜視鏡
Night vision goggles for you
夜視鏡給你看喔
We use night vision goggles and say it's too strong for the eyes
我們用夜視鏡看說 強到眼睛都不行
OK From night vision goggles it should be super strong
OK 從夜視鏡看應該超強
Just 900 OK basically it's not a problem
就900 OK 基本上它不是個問題
OK good
OK 好
Where is the biggest problem with this method
這種方法最大問題在哪裡
Why are you using Core Shield?
你要用Core Shield幹嘛幹嘛一直
you have learned one thing
你都學過一件事情
Yes, if you have learned Welding and Solding today
是如果今天你有沒有學過Welding跟Solding
Welding and Soldering, right?
Welding跟Solding是吧
like that you want that for that line
像那個 你要那個接那個線
When connecting the wires and connecting the soldering, right?
接那個電線要接上那個焊接的時候對不對
if you use that
你如果用那個
If you use Constant to answer with sweat, you can open it with one poke.
用Constant 用汗接的話 你一戳就開了
It opens with one poke, this is called Solding
一戳就開了 這叫Solding
Why because Crystal doesn't match
為什麼 因為Crystal不Match
Crystal Latest is its golden grid not Match
Crystal Latest 就是它的金格不Match
Ok, if it’s the same Match, it’s called Wielding
Ok 一樣Match的話 就是叫Wielding
We call it worthy of sweating, then it will be very tight
我們叫值得汗接 那才會接得很緊
these are the problems
這些都是問題
When you say I'll pack another one
當你說 我就什麼這個又包一個
If you only wrap one, it will fall off after a while.
就包一個的話 過不久就脫落了
Ok because it Crystal is Mismatch
Ok 因為它Crystal是Mismatch
This is the problem, so the current practice is not to do this
這都有這種問題 所以現在的做法就不這樣做
Ok, didn’t I just talk about CDS-11 and cut another ZNS
Ok 剛剛不是講說 CDS-11再砍一個什麼ZNS
Ok don't do it now how do you do it now
Ok 現在都不這樣做 現在怎麼做呢
I used to do this, but now I use alloys
本來就這樣做 現在都是用什麼 用合金的方式
Alloy is just mixing it up, whatever it is, just mixing it up
合金就是把它混在一起 管它三七八一就把它混在一起
Ok why ZNS
Ok 把ZNS 為什麼呢
Because we know that ZN CDS-11 will be faster Match
因為我們知道是ZN CDS-11會比較快Match
Then ZN slowly came in Didget, so it will form a box outside
然後ZN慢慢才Didget進來 所以它就外面會形成一個盒
Then it’s gradual, it’s like quartz and glass can’t be cut, right?
那這樣就漸進式的 漸進式就好像石英跟玻璃不能砍對不對
you put a Gracier in
你把一個Gracier放進去
Eleven on one side and glass on the other
一邊是十一一邊是玻璃
it can be connected together
它就可以連在一起
In the same way, how about using this method?
一樣道理說用這種方式呢
It's much better than before
做出來就比以前好多
Actually, I'm sorry I lied to you just now.
其實剛剛那個很抱歉我騙你們
That's how it was done just now
剛剛那個就是用這種方式來做
then why do you do this
那為什麼要這樣做
because what's the benefit
因為這樣的話就好處什麼
Because it has nothing to do with Size
因為它就跟Size沒有關係
How much Zn is in it matters
有多少Zn在裡面有關係
So at this time I can stretch it to 10 minutes
所以這個時候我就可以拉長到10分鐘
to do it for a few seconds is great though
去做它幾秒鐘雖然很棒
But how do you stop for a few seconds
可是幾秒鐘你怎麼停
Do mass production like this and you have problems
這樣來做大量生產你就有問題
This way you can make blue
這個方式呢就可以做出藍色出來
This powder I just showed you is a solution
這powder我剛剛給你看是solution
OKpowder like this
OKpowder這樣
If you don't believe me you can see that we can
如果你不信的話你看我們可以
make this blue make green
做這個藍的做綠的
Being popular won’t lie to you, right?
做紅的這不會騙你嘛對不對
It is made, you can see that the amount made is so large
它做出來你看喔做出來的量就是這麼大
make it every time
每次做出來
about two grams
大概是兩克左右
two grams of something
兩克什麼東西
Sorry, now a gram is 25,000 yuan
抱歉現在一克是兩萬五千塊錢
so still useful
所以還是有用的
Twenty-five thousand yuan is just my cost
兩萬五千塊錢只是我算成本喔
If you want to go to frame light VG to sell
如果你要到框燈VG賣的話
Two grams will cost you about 40,000 to 50,000.
兩克大概要賣你保守貴四五萬嘛
The most conservative 40,000 to 50,000
最保守四五萬
Not only... I don't know how much
不只...我也不知道多少錢
basically
基本上
Let's take a look
那各位看一下
So its light emission is probably very narrow.
所以它的放光大概都是很窄的
General organic dyes emit light
一般的有機的染料放光
It's probably... If it's a green it's probably like this
大概是...如果說一個綠色大概是這樣
It shines about 1⁄ of its light
它放光大概是只有它的1⁄
What's the benefit?
這什麼好處?
is RGB
就是RGB
If it is RGB, it can be done without FILTER
如果是RGB的話不用FILTER都可以做
this is the best part of it
這是它最棒的地方
Its IdeaCase
它的IdeaCase
Each if 30 Nm
每個如果30個Nm的話
Not even FILTER
連FILTER都不用
Not even green light
就連綠光片都不用
You also know we lose a lot of light
你也知道我們消失很多光
It's because of the green light film
是因為綠光片的關係
So its Country is so good that it explodes
所以它的Country是好到爆掉
Now its Country doesn't work anymore
現在它的Country都不行了
So everyone knows that this is a
所以大家一件事情就知道這是一個
Then you said CDs are poisonous, right?
那你說有CD有毒對不對
You can also use non-toxic
你也可以用無毒的
We now use ZNCINH2
我們現在用ZNCINH2
In this way we can also do anything
用這個方式我們也可以什麼
It can be done without any problem in this space.
可以做出來這個空間道沒有問題
Sorry, the biggest problem with this technique is
很抱歉這個技術最大的問題是
Can only do green light, not red
只能做到綠光不能做紅的
Why?
為什麼?
Because this place costs a lot of ZN
因為這個地方要ZN蠻多的
The more words go to the shorter wavelength
越多的話一直往短波長
so we can't make red light
所以我們做不出紅光
But Liguang we can do well
但是立光我們可以做得很好
there is a problem here
給這邊有問題
OK we make it like this
OK 我們做出來像這樣
15.3489 grams can be made at one time
一次可以做15.3489克
Wow this is posted
哇 這個就發了
OK, if this is currently for sale
OK 這個目前要賣的話
Of course you have to sell to others
當然你要賣給人家
people can do it right away
人家馬上可以做
so to wrap
所以要包裝
so packaging wait a minute i can talk
所以包裝等一下我可以講
you sell this
這個你這樣賣
No company in Taiwan knows what to do
台灣沒有一個公司知道要幹嘛的
OK so how are you going to pack what he's doing
OK 所以你要怎麼去包裝他要幹嘛幹嘛
this is a science
這是一個學問
This is the real knowledge
這才是真的學問
This is no longer a patent
這已經都沒有專利了
why no patents
為什麼沒有專利
20 years of development
20年的發展
The previous patent has long since expired.
前面專利早就過期了
OK so this patent is a patented method
OK 所以這個專利是專利方法
Not in the patent how to synthesize
不是在專利這怎麼合成
OK, supposedly this looks a lot like
OK 按說這個看起來很像
What's so strange about the one that looks like a thread?
很像線的那種有什麼稀奇
Look, turn off the lights and turn on the lights
看好 關起燈來照起燈
this is so beautiful
這這麼漂亮
did you see
有沒有看到
this is full force
這是全力的
OK so the answer is it's gold
OK 所以答案是這是黃金
do not forget
不要忘了
It's more expensive than gold
這比黃金搞得還貴
OK basically
OK 基本上來講
you know what to say
你就知道說
it's a scary thing
這是很恐怖的一件事情
OK we hope to use 100 grams in the future
OK 我們將來希望是以100克
A Batch to do
一個Batch來做
OK
OK
this is what we are trying to do now
這我們現在努力
because it's hard, really hard because
因為很難,真的很難的原因是
We are not from a chemical background
我們不是化工背景的
It's super dangerous to watch him do this kind of thing, let me tell you basically
看他做這種東西超危險的,我給基本上來講的話
So of course you will go in the future
所以那將來當然你要去
If it’s really commercial, it’s one kilogram
真的像commercial的話,他一公斤
You need one kilogram for each background, and I will give you a basic explanation
每個背景要一公斤你才有辦法,我給基本上來講
OK, so what can we do with chemistry?
OK,那我們化學能做什麼東西呢?
In fact, our chemistry is doing some
其實我們化學在做一些
It's powerful in doing this multiplication
它的powerful在做這個multiplication
How do you do some chemical multiplication?
你怎麼做一些chemical multiplication?
does it work
讓它有用嘛
OK, this is us
OK,這才是我們
we make this thing out
我們做出這個東西出來
You want it to have application value
你要讓它有應用價值啊
Of course, the application has a value that shines
當然應用有一個價值是放光
As far as the monitor, we'll talk later
就顯示器,等下我們講
But is there anything else?
但是其他還有沒有其他?
yes, too many
有啊,太多了啊
Let me give you an example, like we are in...
我舉個例子,像我們在...
it's been a long time
這個已經好久了
This was eight years ago, OK
這在八年前的,OK
we develop this, you see
我們就發展這種,你看
This is the one that shines, OK
這個是這個放光的,OK
What to use next to it?
旁邊去用什麼?
used to adjust these so-called obsessions
用去調這些所謂的灌迷
That fan can contain fake, fake ion
那灌迷可以包假,假離子
As for the false ion, it cannot carry two packages like this
那假離子呢,它不能這樣兩個包
It needs to connect two by two, Tang Lunbao
它要兩個兩兩相接,堂倫包
Why? Because it's a problem with entropy
為什麼?因為這是entropy的問題
I won't go into too much detail, it's a question of randomness
我就不多講,這是亂度的問題
It needs to be connected two by two, Tang Lunbao
它要兩兩相相接,堂倫包
So answer first, we can do one thing
所以答案先,我們就可以做一件事情
look
你看喔
Let's use it to detect armor
我們再用它去探測甲
It's very simple. Let's make another
很簡單 我們又合成一個
in a minute
在一分鐘之內
to synthesize a green and a red
去合成一個綠的 一個紅的
it's so easy no problem
這太簡單了 沒有問題
So we synthesized a green one to do rice filling
所以我們就合成一個綠的同樣去做灌米
wrap it in this place
把它包在這個地方
So when armor cuts in
所以當甲砍進去的時候
It may be red and green cut together
它就有可能是紅跟綠砍在一起
Also follow red with red, also follow green with green
也跟紅跟紅 也跟綠跟綠
It doesn't matter, the probability of red and green is 1.2
沒關係 紅跟綠的機率是1.2
So as long as red and green are cut together, there will be energy transfer
所以只要紅跟綠砍在一起 就有能量轉移
green turns red
綠的會轉成紅的
OK we see the green ones disappear and the red ones grow
OK 我們就看到綠的會消失 紅的會長大
is it really like this
真的是這樣子嗎
OK the answer is yes
OK 答案是確實是這樣
OK look
OK 你看
So the answer is when red and green
所以答案是當紅跟綠的話
you know it will grow to
你就知道說 它會長到
The green one will disappear when the armor is dropped
綠的會消失 掉甲的時候
OK until halfway it doesn't move why
OK 直到一半它就不動 為什麼
Because the others are green green red red it does not move
因為其他是綠綠 紅紅 它不動
So this is also saying that the theory is right.
所以這也正評說理論是對的
OK, let me tell you that it was originally this color
OK 這跟你講說本來是這個顏色
The more red the color becomes
紅的越多就變成顏色
so you see it's useful
所以你看 很有用
OK basically
OK 基本上
If you don't believe me let's see another
如果你不信的話 我們再看看一個
This is what I cooperated with Fang Junping and the others
這是我跟方俊平他們合作的
OK basically
OK 基本上
it was a long time ago
這也好久以前了
This was at least eight or nine years ago
這個起碼是八九年前的 OK
you see we can go
你看 我們可以去
After we synthesized this thing
就我們合成這個東西以後
Teacher Fang and the others synthesized this so-called
那方老師他們去合成這個所謂的叫做
called
叫做
This is Gout
Astia Guta
juta gujami
Guta Gujami
this is very simple
這個很簡單
Guta Gujami is the one with eggs
Guta Gujami就卵子的那個
help me the most over there
幫我那邊最多
OK because the egg needs to
OK 因為卵子要
something to find sperm
東西找精子
OK, if the sperm and egg are going to combine
OK 就精卵要結合的話
next to the embryo of your egg
你的卵的胚胎旁邊
must have this thing
一定要有這個東西
So let's take this as an egg
所以我們就把這個當作卵子
agree again
再同意一次
Let's take this as an egg
我們就把這個當作卵子
Take this Guta Gujami
把這個Guta Gujami
use it with a SS linkage
把它用一個SS linkage
then in this place
然後在這個地方
this reverting action
這個還原的動作
become SH
變成SH
cut it
跟它砍
then i can say
那我可以講說
cut with this semiconductor
跟這個半導體砍
It's all cut with a flow machine
都是用流機去砍
OK and G also use streamers
OK 跟G也是用流機
ok then why
OK 那為什麼呢
Because if the flow machine cuts it
因為流機跟它砍的話
about 20 kcal
大概是20千卡
The energy is 20 kcal, this stick
就能量是20千卡 這個棒
Flow and G are the most stable
流跟G的話是最穩定的
Flow and G is 41 kcal
流跟G是41千卡
so why
所以為什麼
All G's Neoplas use stream cutting
所有的G的Neoplas都用流砍
OK, that's easy to remember
OK 那這很好記嘛
If you want to test
你要考試的話就是
Flowing G years Flowing G years
流G歲月 流G歲月
Flow and G are the best OK
流跟G是最棒的 OK
So Liu and G cut is the best
所以流跟G砍的是最棒的
basically
基本上來講
This stream we use
這個我們有用的流
So after chopping it up
所以砍上去以後
just treat it as a soft paper
就把它當作一個軟紙
so we find gold
所以我們就找金子
We use C2 circle
我們用C2圈
It's the gold of the sea urchin
是海膽的金子
look
你看
Cut with sea urchin gold
用海膽金子一砍
Everything is included in this place
全部都是包在這個地方
Our NEOPARTY are all cut in this place
我們NEOPARTY都砍在這個地方
this place where the spun cut to gold
砍到金子的spun的這個地方
I said
我說
Maybe it has this place
搞不好它本來有這個地方
very simple
很簡單
Let's take that bone off
我們就把那骨頭上拿掉
We use MANOS
我們用MANOS
MANOS will be cut everywhere
MANOS都到處會砍
You can see that MANOS will be cut everywhere
你看MANOS就到處會砍
So the answer it's really specific
所以答案它真的是很specific
then you say this
那你說這個
Then why we are developing
後來為什麼我們在發展
because it's too poisonous
因為太毒了
CD is too poisonous
CD太毒了
so cd now
所以CD現在
No
沒有
This semiconductor of CD
CD的這個半導體
no one is using what
沒有人在用在什麼
The Bio-Medical Impossible
Bio-Medical不可能的事情
The reason is too poisonous
原因就是太毒了
OK so now instead
OK 所以轉而現在
The most used one is Materials Science
最用最多的就是Materials Science
OK that Materials Science
OK 那Materials Science
everyone knows
各位都知道
I won't talk about this
這個我就不講了
I jump over there are too many
我跳過去有太多
OK we see
OK 我們看到
monitor
顯示器
Future Trends
未來的趨勢
OK because you can draw this number
OK 因為可以抽這個號碼
This was announced last week
這個就是上禮拜公佈的
It's called REC2020
叫做REC2020
it's 2020
就是2020年的時候
Specifications for all displays Highest quality
所有顯示器的規格最高品質
This is the Color specification
就是這個Color specification
What about the Color specification?
這個Color specification呢
Currently it looks like there is only one reachable
目前看起來只有一個可以達到
frame root way
就是框根道
Why? Because it RGB is the best
為什麼?因為它RGB是最棒的
This is Sony made RGB
這個就Sony做出來了RGB的
basically speaking
基本上來講的話
Made it with frame root
用框根道做出來了
How many ways are there to frame the roots?
那框根道做法有幾種嗎?
one is you know
一種就是你也知道
It is probably Sony's type that uses this on both sides.
大概是Sony的是用這個兩邊這樣打的
Just use Blu to make the green frame root
就是用Blu去打綠色框根道
White light comes out from the red frame
跟紅色框根道出來是白光
The other CM
那另外CM的
The root B volume of the box is to use FIM
跟框根B卷就是用FIM
This FIM is the same
這種FIM也是一樣
green and red
用綠跟紅
Then the following is with Blu-ray
然後下面是用藍光
because blu ray is the best
因為藍光最好做
Blue LED is the best
藍光LED最好做
Use 460 to dial 520 and 630
用460去打520跟630出來
OK, this is white light
OK,這出來就是白光
This approach is OK
這種做法OK
Then there is the Micro chip
那另外就是Micro chip
Just put it DD now
現在就是把它DD
the red and green
那個紅跟綠的
D to what?
D到什麼?
Micro chip aspect
Micro chip方面
That Micro chip is LED to what?
那個Micro chip就是LED到什麼?
Blue, ah, what is blue when it shines
的Blue 啊Blue放光出來就是什麼
is white light
就是白光
OK, there are these three ways
OK 有這種 這三種做法
That's probably the most
那大概現在最
The biggest trend is probably this
最大的趨勢大概就是這個
Film does the most
Film做最多
OK, so actually we have chosen Film
OK 所以其實我們有選擇Film
doing ok
在做 OK
That
那
Kuan Sheng Dao can do it very well
寬生道可以很好做出來
the hardest part
最難的地方
How to cut together with Polymer
是怎麼跟Polymer去砍在一起
become this Film
變成這張Film
Oh that's a science
喔 那是個學問
We spent almost two years
我們花了快兩年的時間
OK everyone, no need to take pictures
OK 各位不用照相
Because of this I just write one
因為這個我是隨便寫一個
Because we're going to announce OK basically talk
因為我們要公布 OK 基本上來講話
So everyone, one thing is very simple
所以大家一件事情就很簡單
You see we can use this kind of Film
你看我們可以用這種Film
make a green and red
去做一個綠色跟紅的
OK green and red OK basically
OK 綠跟紅的 OK 基本上
Ah, if he doesn't shine
啊 他如果不照光
Then this color OK basically speaks
那就這種顏色 OK 基本上來講話
that's in this place
那在這個地方
We make a Film
我們做出一張Film
Come on, let's take a look at this Film for you
來 我們看看這個Film給你看
This Film is what we made OK
這張Film就是我們做出來了 OK
you see you use blue
你看 你用藍色的
Use blue, this is all blue
用藍 這個都藍色
look at blu ray
你看就藍光
fat is white
胖的話是白色的
Because it's only green and red
因為這只有綠跟紅
Ah, adding blue is white
啊 加上藍就是白的
OK turn off the lights is like
OK 關燈就是好像
Because this blu-ray is actually
因為這個藍光其實是
I spark blue light
我激發藍光啦
but he is white
可是他是白的
Ah, if you are unlucky
啊 如果不幸的話
I don't want the whole paper
我整張紙就不要
don't focus
不要聚焦
If the whole paper is illuminated, it will look like this
整張紙讓它 illuminate的話就變這樣子
just white light
就白光
OK, it's white
OK,就是白的
So this is its niche
所以這個就是它的 niche
It can produce a white light
它就是可以產生一張白光的
Send this this display
發這個這個 display
Then let you do all the following actions
然後讓你去做所有的下面的動作
OK, it can be done even without filter
OK,甚至不用 filter 都可以做
Why? Because each one is
為什麼?因為每一個都是
Both are very, very sharp bandwidth
都是一個非常非常 sharp 的 bandwidth
OK, basically
OK,基本上
What about the bright paper point, and its application in luminescence
那亮紙點呢,在發光上的應用呢
just said passive
剛剛講是被動的
That is, you directly use the blu-ray to pump to get it
就是你直接用藍光去 pump 得到它
if you want to be active you have to take the initiative
如果你要 active 你要主動的話
That is QLED
那就是 QLED 嘛
Sorry about the LEDs on Quadrant Road
就匡登道的 LED 抱歉
Quadrant Road's LED so far
匡登道的 LED 到目前為止
Taiwan's development
台灣的發展
that's too far behind
那落後太多了
OK, basically
OK,基本上來講
because i'm doing chemistry
因為我是在做化學
I'm not doing engineering
我並不在做 engineering
In fact, I have been calling for it for five or six years.
其實我早就呼籲了五六年了
ok , basically talk
OK,基本上來講話
Or Taiwan has done too little
還是台灣做得太少了
That's 18% done recently
那最近已經做出 18% 了
OK, I think 18% this
OK,我覺得 18% 這個
Including public and educational personnel are very useful
包括公教人員都滿好用的
That's 18% OK, basically
就是 18% OK,基本上
You just remember 18%
你就記得 18% 就對了
ok , basically talk
OK,基本上來講話
Then why couldn't it be done before?
那以前為什麼都做不出來
You look good, let me tell you, everyone
你看好,我跟你講,各位
this
這個
No Fundamental
沒有Fundamental
you don't want to do anything
你休想做任何東西
OK, this is developed to be 8 temperature ratio
OK 這個發展出來是8溫比
on MIT
就MIT的
With this Broadic
跟這個Broadic
This is in the electrical department
這個就是在電機系的
This is the electrical department
這個是電機系的
this is from the chemistry department
這是化學系的
The whole combination of motor and chemistry
要電機跟化學整個組合
you have a way
你才有辦法
OK, there is also a physics department
OK 那還有個物理系的
There is also a physics department here
這邊還有個物理系的
then why
那為什麼呢
Because the reason why it couldn't be done before is because
因為以前都做不出來的原因是
we only know now
我們現在才知道
because when you use electron light
因為當你用電子光的時候
You used a bunch of electronics and electricity to come out
你用了一堆電子跟電動出來
This electron is too electric
這個電子太電
too many electrons
電子已經太多了
too much for a physical benefit
太多就一個物理的利益
Called the reverse OJ Process
叫做反的OJ Process
is that it will wipe it all off
就是它會把它全部消光掉
Just the opposite OJ
就反的OJ
wait a minute i'll talk about this
等一下我會講這個
Just the opposite OJ Process
就反的OJ Process
OJ Process Logically speaking it should be
OJ Process 照理講是應該
one becomes two
一個變兩個
it is now two become
它現在是兩個變成
Gone
沒了
OK so when a thing is
OK 所以當一件事情是
that now they are smart
那現在他們很聰明
they are here
他們就是在這個地方
smooth it
消平它
Flatten two Bank Gap
消平兩個Bank Gap
Let many electrons
讓電子很多的時候
you can come here, come here
可以到這邊來 在這邊來
The whole thing is Dilocalize
整個就是Dilocalize
so it can be accessed from
所以它就可以從
1% to 18%
1%到18%
OK look at this
OK 你看這個
This is the political and economic world in 2013
這就是在2013年是政經全世界
OK
OK
The current problem is unstable
現在的問題在不穩定
If the stability is overcome
穩定度克服的話
I'm sorry, we all have been doing it for so long, probably we don't need to do it
抱歉了我們大家做偶類做那麼久大概不用做了
basically talk
基本上來講話
Our laboratory is now approximately
我們實驗室現在大概
we follow
我們跟
With the cooperation of Ocean University, we can probably make it invisible
海洋大學合作我們大概可以做出不露出來
OK but not high
OK但是不高
but this
但是這個
This is a question about the Five-Eyed Buddha Realm
這個是一個五眼佛界的問題
if this is right if bangwit30nm
如果這是對的話如果Bangwit30個nm
Mineral energy is one
礦能一的都是一的
OK, if the stability is enough, who can compare with him?
OK如果穩定度夠那誰跟他比
You two compare
你兩個比啊
OK, so this is basically what Taiwan should have developed long ago
OK所以這個基本上是台灣早就應該發展
It's a pity that none of them came out. The other one is the solar battery.
很可惜都沒有出來另外一個就太陽能電池
OK, the solar battery is basically
OK那太陽電池的話基本上
That's already a problem with the solar battery.
那已經太陽電池問題不行
because of that
因為那個
The leanant next to it is too long
旁邊的leagant太長了
Electricity can't be transmitted
電子電動沒辦法傳出去
Now use the inorganic method to develop it in Toronto, use the inorganic method, use the short chain or inorganic method
現在就用無機的方式在多倫多那邊發展出來用無機的方式用短鏈的或無機的方式呢
He can do the same with 8.55%
他就可以做到8.55%也是同樣的
Bowendy and
Bowendy跟
Bobic
Bobic
OK you know one thing is
OK你就知道一件事情是
How can this be done without combining electrical physics and chemistry?
這個不結合電機物理跟化學哪有辦法
OK so this has to be integrated
OK所以這都要整合
It just doesn't work if you don't integrate
不整合根本就是行不通的
Don't shoot birds randomly, it's impossible
你不要亂槍打鳥 不可能
You don't have this kind of random shooting
這種亂槍打鳥 你沒有機裡
It's impossible for you to shoot wildly.
你要亂槍打鳥 都是不可能的一件事情
OK so one thing for everyone and this is to visit Demental
OK 所以大家一件事情 這個就是要訪Demental
You're going to move forward, can you find a way, okay?
你要去往前走 你能查個辦法 好不好
So let me tell you why this loose to the solar cell is
那這就跟你講說 為什麼這個寬鬆到太陽電池是
is a one
是一個 一個
Future goals Let me give you a very simple example, you see, this is OJ Process
未來的目標 我舉個很簡單的例子 你看喔 這就是OJ Process
Look, a Fortone is punched up, this one has electric
你看喔 一個Fortone打上去 這個有電動
OK this is no battery yes this electronics if I think solar
OK 這沒有電池 對 這電子如果 我覺得太陽能
You also know that Mr. Lin and the others know each other very well.
你也知道 像林老師他們最熟了
pair a solar cell
對 一個太陽能電池
OK if your dye is like dye brightening
OK 如果你的染料 像染料光明化
You go from 700C light to 300 to 400
你從700C光到300 到400
You inspire 400 and you also get 700
你激發400 你也得到700
Yes Excite 500 to 700 you from 500 to 700
對 激發500到700 你從500到700
All the energy in between is wasted.
這中間的能量全部浪費掉的啊
Because it's better to let it come down here before going out, right?
因為它就不如讓它下來到這邊 才出去嘛 對不對
So but it's so loose that it's not the same as you get excited to this place
所以 但是寬鬆到不一樣 你一激發到這個地方
I think it’s good to stimulate 400, here it’s 400
我覺得激發400好 這邊400好了
Let's say it's 800 here
這邊假如是800好了
From 400 to this place it can be done with a very simple action
從400到這個地方 它可以用一個很簡單的動作
that is
就是
When this place comes down, when this place goes up, OJ process
這個地方下來,這個地方上去就OJ process
this down, this up
這個下來,這個上去
You can use this place once resonance
你可以用這個地方一次resonance
After coming down, this tiredness will change to two
下來以後把這個疲乏上去就變兩個
That is to say, I stimulate an energy
也就是說我激發一個能量
But it becomes two electrons on top
可是變成兩個電子在上面
ok, this is called up conversion
ok,這叫up conversion
ok, so use this way
ok,所以用這種方式
In theory you can reach 66%
理論上你可以達到66%
basically speaking
基本上來講的話
This is where everyone tends to go wrong
這是大家趨之落誤的
ok, basically since that Nucia brought it up
ok,基本上從那個紐西亞他提出來以後
So far I can't really prove how much
到現在其實沒辦法去證明多少
But now with current technology
但是現在以目前的技術
Personally, I think this will definitely break through in the future.
我個人覺得這將來一定會突破了
ok, how to break through
ok,怎麼突破吧
it's an interesting thought
它是一個很有趣的思維
just tell everyone about this
就跟各位講這件事情
Okay, I probably won't talk about it
好,下來我大概就不講了
because talking too much
因為講太多了
In addition, it is like shining
另外就是像發光的
Sorry, gold can shine too
抱歉,金也可以發光
You see, the gold that is stepped on quickly does not shine
你看,快踩的金是不發光
right
對不對
Then when it is greater than 1.5 nm to 50 nm
那到大於1.5個nm到50個nm的時候
We're called, you all know it's called Surface Plasma Justice
我們叫做,你都知道叫做表面電漿公正
Right, gold has color, everyone knows
對不對,金就有顏色,大家都知道
right , but it doesn ' t shine
對不對,可是它不發光
But when you are as small as 1.5nm
可是你對小到1.5nm的時候
what has become, quantize
已經變成什麼,quantize
Discrete phenomenon
有Discrete的現象
it will glow
它就會發光
This is what our Sense made
這是我們Sense做出來的
you see it glows red
你看它會發紅光
In red light in this place
在紅光在這個地方
what shall we do this time
那我們這次怎麼做呢
what is our bread
我們的外面包的是什麼東西
Packet shift derivative
外面是包移導數
OK we wrap gold with shifted derivatives
OK 我們用移導數包金
How do you say that eating is not boring? Use the shift derivative package
你說怎麼吃不無聊用移導數包
Because we already know that there are 4 SH in the shift derivative
因為我們早知道移導數裡面有4個SH
it definitely has a chance
它絕對有機會了
This is your Nulling OK
這個就是你的Nulling嘛 OK
basically it's small
基本上它又小
So it can be used as Template
所以它可以當Template
we wrap it up together you see
我們把它包起來一起 你看
look how useful it is
你看它多好用
Basically you see, using the shift derivative package comes out as
基本上你看 移用移導數包出來就是
It 1.2 Neyometer
它1.2個Neyometer
it shines
它放光
Space 1 to 0.1 to 0.3
空間1到0.1到0.3之間
It's easy if you're unlucky
不幸的話很簡單嘛
Is there a shift derivative in this?
這個裡面有沒有移導數
Look, we'll just use one
看好 我們只要用一個
So the N station of Insulin's Digest
所以Insulin的Digest的N站
Go chop it down and it won't shine when it comes out
去砍到它以後出來就不放光
Insulin
就是把Insulin
After dropping this Insulin and that Decomposed
把這個Insulin那個Decomposed掉以後
it doesn't shine
它就不放光
So of course Insulin is on top of that
所以當然Insulin就是在這上面
We published this in NQ1 in 2011
這個我們2011年發表在NQ1
OK now it has been stuffed 148 times
OK 現在已經被塞了148次了
Basically someone must use it
基本上一定有人用
because i never tan myself
因為我從來沒有曬過我自己
So this 148 is posted by others
所以這148就是別人曬的
So the answer is definitely useful
所以答案是一定有用
We can use it as image
我們可以當作image
Then this image red image
那這image 紅色的image
the one in the muscle
就在muscle的那個
That sale is very useful
那個sale上面是很好用的
Basically I am now a lot of people like us to
基本上我這個現在很多人像我們要
So they should also be doing this approach
所以他們應該也在做這方面的approach
basically speaking
基本上來講的話
especially insulin you know
尤其insulin你也知道
Diabetes is America's number one disease
糖尿病是美國第一大病
Why is everyone so fat
為什麼每個人都胖到不行
So the answer is that there is no way
所以答案件事情是沒辦法的事情
I don't talk about anything else
其他我都不講
like these
像這些
what do we do some fuseale
我們做一些fuseale幹嘛幹嘛
Just now, Vice President Wang, you said
剛剛王副院長你講說
i do everything
我什麼都做
do nothing wrong
沒有錯什麼都做
basically speaking
基本上來講的話
You just make a different size
你就做不同的這種size
What is the fuseale including this shave dependent doing?
包括這個shave dependent的fuseale幹嘛幹嘛
In fact, we do a lot of this phenomenon
其實我們做很多這種現象
even we can use fine silver alloy
甚至我們可以用精銀合金
toon its prasma band
toon它的prasma band
To do opv, we also do a lot of this
去做opv我們也做很多這方面
I won't talk about this
這個我就不多講
That's actually
那其實
if you give me an hour
如果給我一小時
I can put this into perspective
我可以把這個講得超棒的
but there is no time now
可是現在也沒有時間
We do a lot of business with refugee machinery
就我們做很多生意難民機材
So just now the student of mine
所以剛剛其實那個我的學生
my former students
以前我的學生
Chen Junan told me that he was doing New Long
陳俊安跟我講說他在做New Long
Do Stem Cell in doing New Long
在做New Long方面做Stem Cell
In fact, we also do a lot of this
其實我們也做蠻多這方面的
But we do his Imaging
但是我們做他的Imaging
We do a lot of things like Imaging
我們做很多這種Imaging方面的東西
i can basically talk
我可以基本上來講話
What about the last one?
最後一張呢
Let me tell you one thing is this
就跟你講一件事情是這張
This is the last one
這最後一張啦
This is a wheat field in England
這張是英國的麥田
English wheat fields, right?
英國麥田對不對
This British wheat field is really good
這英國麥田真的是好棒
when i see this
當我看到這張以後
i just know
我才知道說
It turns out that the Kangbang I studied is exactly the same
原來跟我研究的康邦是一模一樣
basically talk
基本上來講話
Then I'm going this way now
那我現在就是往這邊走
I'm going to Brain Research now
我現在就往Brain Research
Because the answer is that I personally think one thing is
因為答案是我個人認為一件事情是
our future generations
將來我們的下一代
The next generation can already live to be 100 years old
下一代已經可以活到100歲了
But what's the point of living a very unhappy life, right?
可是活得很不快樂的什麼屁用了對不對
So the answer to one thing is
所以答案一件事情是
Your Brain is the most important
你的Brain最重要
i didn't lie to you
我沒有騙你的事情
I really think Brain Research
我真覺得Brain Research
Basically, we must go in the future
基本上將來是一定要走的
because our brains
因為我們腦子
nothing has changed in a thousand years
一千年來都沒有變化
But our knowledge has skyrocketed ten million times
可是我們的知識已經暴漲了一千萬倍
this is our biggest problem
這是我們的最大問題
So how to do Brain Research
所以怎麼去做Brain Research
i just matter
我就是很重要
Then I am researching Slautonium and Milatonian
那我在研究就是Slautonium跟Milatonian
this piece
這一塊
because it's my specialty
因為這是我的專長
I just said what kind of specialty is this?
剛剛我講過這什麼專長
well in this place
好 在這個地方
I just stop at this place
我就Stop在這個地方
OK
OK
I just said that
那我剛剛也講過
actually, I
其實我
Because there are very few Ph.D.
因為現在博士班都很少
Look at the doctoral class in recent years
你看博士班這幾年
Only these few people in five years
五年才這幾個人
So I'm all on my post-out
所以我都是靠我的Post-out
OK all my money Sug in my post-out
OK 我的錢全部Sug在我的Post-out
basically talk
基本上來講話
OK that's about it
OK 大概講到這邊
thank you all
謝謝大家
clap your hands
拍掌
Hope you all have one
希望大家真的有一個
still enjoy
還是享受的
enjoy beauty
享豔
good i think
好 我想
Would you like to have a drink first?
你要不要先做一做喝口
I still have a lot of experience
我還有很多經歷人
You see how Energetic he is
你看他多Energetic
ok is there any problem
好 有沒有問題
for this I
這個我
wait a minute my wife tell me
等一下 我太太跟我講一聲
you say
你說
every time you speak
你每次演講
like a movie star
就跟一個電影明星一樣
But you come home a worm
可是你回家一條蟲
sure so
確定這樣
I'm sure
我確定這樣
thank you for your speech
謝謝你的演講
I want to ask you about the first half
我想請教你就有關前半部
because of my
因為我那個
Kaohsiung gas explosion incident
高雄氣爆事件
because it has that explosive
因為它有那個爆炸的
Later I went to refer to some chemistry
後來我去參考一些化學的
Seems like it could also be done in this optomechanical way
好像它可以也是用這種光機的方式
To see if there is chemistry that try
去看是不是有化學的那一 try
Or that try to get into the ingredients of these explosives
或者那一 try 進去這些炸藥的成分
I'll ask for advice
我會請教一下就是說
Why like this way
為什麼像類似這種的方式
In fact, when they were dealing with incidents similar to those in Kaohsiung
實際他們在處理類似高雄事件的時候
It does not detect whether there are chemical components of violent substances
它沒有去檢測是不是有暴力物的那些化學成分
actually i tell you
其實我跟你講
If you want to speak from a spectroscopic point of view
如果你要從光譜學的角度來講的話
if specific few
如果是特定的幾個
For example, if you measure IR vibration spectrum or Lyman spectrum
譬如說你測 IR 震動光譜或者萊曼光譜
These things if you want specific
這些東西如果你想特定的
specific few
特定的幾個
In fact, these can be used in the analysis of data
其實這些在 data 的 analysis 是可以
can do not a problem
可以做的 不是個問題
this can definitely be done
這絕對可以做的
So one thing for everyone is to say
所以大家一件事情就是說
We are actually from Taiwan...
我們其實台灣的...
His advance is measured after a plan
他這部先進是一計測出來以後
What is that data for?
那個data要幹嘛
That's where we're not very advanced
那是我們很不先進的地方
why i give an example
為什麼我舉個例子
like our LCMAS
像我們的LCMAS
Incredible, including the chemistry department
不可思議 包括化學系也是一樣
The opera you typed out will tell you
你打出來那個opera跟你講說
I don't know, I don't know what
我不知道呀 這不知道什麼東西
Our data bank is completely inadequate
我們data bank是完全不足的
Now students and people know one thing
現在學生化人都知道一件事情
What are you going to screen for?
你要去篩選什麼要 幹嘛幹嘛
Look at that Half or MIT
你看那個Half or MIT
that data bank
那個data bank
how many people are going to do what
有多少人要去做什麼
How big is the data bank
data bank有多大
The accumulation of how much money and the accumulation of people
那多少錢的堆積跟人的堆積
We never do software stuff
我們從不做軟體的東西
I can tell you about the question you asked
你問的問題我可以跟你講說
In terms of explosives, data bank
以爆裂物來講data bank
absolutely doable
絕對是可行的
It's a pity we don't do this kind of thing
可惜我們就不去做這種事情
We have instruments coming out and don't know what
我們有儀器出來不曉得什麼東西
this is our biggest problem
這是我們的最大問題
OK
好不好
Thanks
謝謝
What is the problem
有什麼問題
The crazy question is okay
crazy的問題沒關係啊
crazy question
瘋狂的問題
I'm always full of crazy ideas
我經常都是瘋狂想法
I didn't lie to you
我沒有騙你啊
right
對不對
but crazy idea
可是瘋狂想法
one out of ten is enough
十個中一個就夠了
it's obvious
這很明顯的事情
A person's life
人的一生
you have to go crazy
你也要瘋狂一下
somehow
某種程度是這樣子
Is it already
現在是不是已經有
the light therapy device
那個光治療的設備
under that of Taiwan
太台灣的那個之下
in treatment
有在治療
Did you say light therapy?
你說光治療是不是
Buddha as much as that Thorpe
佛多達那個Thorpe
Is this most likely skin cancer?
這個最多就是皮膚癌嘛
What about social traps?
還有社會陷害嘛
OK, this is probably the most light therapy
OK 這個大概是最多的光治療
submerged
潛沉了啦
Because of the light
因為光喔
sorry for something
很抱歉一些事情
biggest problem with light
光的最大問題
high energy of light
是光的能量高
I say visible light
我講是可見光
visible light to that
可見光到那個
when in infrared
進紅外的時候
energy is still too high
能量還是太高了
So generally speaking in terms of infrared
所以一般以進紅外來講的話
Can penetrate at most
最多能穿透
about 0.6 cm
大概差不多是0.6公分
already amazing
就已經了不起了
so here's the problem
所以這是問題
longer wavelength
越長波長
It should be deeper
就是應該是越深入
OK basically
OK 基本上
But it doesn't shine, basically
可是它不放光啊 基本上來講
So you know what MRI like we come out
所以你就知道像我們出來什麼核磁共振
that long wavelength
那種這麼長波長
it can penetrate this no problem
它就可以穿透這個沒有問題
But the shorter words
可是越短的話
It's the problem here
它這個問題就出在這個地方
so light therapy
所以光治療
Sorry to tell you one thing is to say
很抱歉 跟各位講一件事情就是說
You're probably going to do a dive.
大概你就做潛程了嘛
OK that's all except for you to have the surgery
OK 那生成除了你開刀
I'll do light therapy later
以後再去做光治療
Otherwise it is Target Oriented
要不然就是Target Oriented
So Target is
所以Target就是
is the target
就是標靶
OK target
OK 標靶
And the target has no light
而且標靶它沒有光啊
No, they use monooxygen now.
沒有啊 現在都是用單氧嘛
monoxide, right?
單太氧對不對
So you target after that place
所以你標靶在那個地方以後
you can be like we actually are
你可以像我們實際上是
i didn't talk
我是沒有講的
you can
你可以
You can take that and we call it Endopoxide
你可以那個帶那個我們叫Endopoxide
OK it can
OK 它可以
It can be released into single oxygen
它可以release出來變成單氧
That is also possible
那也是可以這樣做啊
It can automatically do that without lighting
就不用照光 它也可以自動那個
but you want a target
可是你要標靶
you don't have a target
你沒有標靶不行
Because everything kills the impossible
因為什麼都殺那不可能的事情
OK
好不好
any left
還有沒有
No, we thank Professor Zhou
沒有 我們就謝謝周教授
ok thank you thank you thank you all
好 謝謝 謝謝 謝謝大家
Thank you.
Thank you.